all
Speaker 1: right welcome to today's news and i'm matt taivi i'm
michael
Speaker 2: tracy i think
Speaker 1: you're michael tracy and i bet there's lots of folks here just uh bubbling over with love and the milk of uh
Speaker 3: loving kindness who just can't wait to
um
Speaker 3: Share their comments with us. We're gonna we're gonna
All the
Speaker 4: productive feedback all the
Speaker 5: productive feedback that we're expecting and we'll engage with some of it
But
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): we should start off by wishing everybody a happy St. Patrick's Day, which is technically tomorrow. You see I'm Adorned in the traditional colors of my
Speaker 7: people. I am half Irish Michael. You're a little bit Irish.
Speaker 8: I
Speaker 8: No, I'm
Speaker 9: half Irish. I'm half Irish, half Italian. And it's just that
Speaker 10: nobody ever thinks that I'm Irish or even though I have my last name, Tracy, is the Irish spelling of the surname. If anything, it's always
Speaker 11: just people being perpetually confused when they find that I'm not Jewish. I don't know if they're disappointed or if they are pleased. It can vary.
Yeah.
um
Speaker 11: yeah i always tell them you know i wish i was jewish i guess my iq would be a few points higher but other than that no i'm not true i
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): probably could have gone to like one of those cool uh summer camps where like you can get it subsidized and stuff like that's what all the jewish friends i had growing up did but i just i was just stuck
Speaker 14: going to like the the town pool
i i did
Speaker 15: the town pool as well i went i went to
a
to
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): a semi crappy uh crappy summer camp i didn't get get to do anything fancy i didn't get to do um you know like the uh the dirty dirty dancing camp uh or any of that stuff didn't go to the
Speaker 17: poconos um where did you grow up michael
uh new
Speaker 17: jersey new jersey okay where
Speaker 18: like where you are in jersey
Speaker 19: city no no uh essex county so um roundabouts where the sopranos lived
Yes.
Speaker 20: Gotcha. Gotcha. All right. So, uh, and you went to high school there, the whole thing?
Speaker 21: Yeah, the whole thing. I, um,
I share a
Speaker 21: hometown with, uh, justice Samuel Alito.
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): Ah,
yeah.
West
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): Cobble, New Jersey, if people are interested. I mean, it's easily Google-able, so it's not like I'm giving up any kind of sensitive information there. Well,
Speaker 22: I mean, you don't
want to
Speaker 22: be giving away your exact geolocation. No, it's not my current location. Yeah,
Speaker 23: not your current location. But
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): notable...
The
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): persons associated with my hometown include Samuel Alito, G. Gordon Liddy, and myself.
Speaker 24: G. Gordon Liddy. Outstanding. You know what? He's crazy. Yogi Berra. Did you ever read his book? Did you ever read Will? I
never read his
Speaker 25: book, no.
It's one of
Speaker 26: the great
Speaker 27: autobiographies of all time. He's absolutely nuts, but it's a great book. Like John Lennon wrote him a thank you letter when he read it. Oh, really?
Speaker 28: Yeah. Is that when
Speaker 27: he became like
Speaker 29: a talk radio host? Yeah.
It
Speaker 29: was in between. It was sort
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): of in between his prison sentence and then later, before it became a media figure. Really, what's amazing
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): about the book is that it speeds through all the stuff that was supposed to be the saleable part about Watergate, and then the book really takes off when he's in prison and ends up becoming this
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): major...
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): prison leader who wiretaps the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): warden and does all kinds of crazy shit. Anyway, I'm rambling. Lots of stuff happened this weekend. We're going to get to as much of it as we can, and then we're going to engage on a broader question about whether...
The
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): podcasts
Speaker 32: are worse than the mainstream press. Michael, you have pretty definite feelings about this.
Speaker 33: Well, hold on. Before we go any further, Matt, let's underscore
Speaker 11: that there is no truth at all to these vicious rumors that the real name of the show.
is
Speaker 11: something like the pedophile report or private private party no
Speaker 34: no no we
Speaker 21: straightforward
Speaker 11: just news uh broadcasting title is as you can see today's news and there's nothing beyond that so please pipe down with all these
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): nasty insinuations
Speaker 36: And the pizza, the slice of pizza looking
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): thing is actually just an A in
a
Speaker 17: Swedish wingding font. It's actually just a
Speaker 11: formatting error that we never bothered to fix in the logo. So there's nothing beyond that.
Speaker 37: But, you know, sometimes those little flaws are what
Speaker 39: makes art great,
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): right? True. So true. It's not suggestive at all. not we're not suggesting
that
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): that pizza's code for anything. Grape Soda was
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): not a backup name for the show. Neither was Lolita Express. So we probably would
Speaker 42: have, I mean, Lolita Express, had we hypothetically wanted to give the show a secret secondary
name.
it's
Speaker 42: almost seemed a little bit too on the nose.
Speaker 44: Yeah. If we're
Speaker 45: honest, I was more in favor of it than you were. So it's none of those things.
Speaker 46: It's today's news. And it's like Walter. Imagine Walter Cronkite, but on a sub stack live stream.
Speaker 46: that's what today's news is
Speaker 47: that's exactly what this this is i mean i was actually getting walter cronkite vibes as we were just talking
um
Speaker 48: walter cronkite actually got caught meeting with epstein did you know that did
he really in the in
Speaker 11: the first production of the latest epstein
files
I'm
Speaker 10: going through them right so this is like December 19th 20th or something and they have like all these you know just unorganized photos of things because Jeffrey Epstein for one thing might have been the most photographed man
in
Speaker 46: history I don't know how many I mean what do you just have a constant team of photographers surrounding him
Speaker 46: 24 7 it's bizarre but i look at a guy like so he's at his new mexico ranch right and he's meeting with two people they're sitting on a couch they have like a little platter of hors d'oeuvres i'm looking at the guy he's chatting to and i said wait is that walter cronkite and then sure enough like it is walter cronkite i guess he ended up getting walter cronkite to come over to the new mexico
Speaker 49: ranch and like have a little sit down i don't know so you never you can never fail to
Speaker 50: find somebody new who's like quote-unquote implicated in this
Speaker 51: Well, we got to clearly we got to destroy Cronkite's reputation as quickly as possible. He's got to be liquidated and maybe
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): arrested, according to a certain Oscars host. But we'll get to that in a moment. So
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): the media world is suddenly exploding
because
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): you
Speaker 53: know sort of the biggest figure in American media right now is that correct to say or is Joe Rogan the biggest figure in
Speaker 54: American media is Tucker or is it Tucker no probably by volume it's it's Rogan
yeah I guess
Speaker 55: but if what
you
Speaker 56: mean by biggest is most influential most influential yeah I think that might still have to go to Rogan yeah
Speaker 57: but you know a reasonable case could be made probably one way or another for both of them
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): Okay. Well, Tucker came out over the weekend and in an announcement that replicated an earlier incident about being tracked by FISA, announced that he was being, that the CIA was monitoring
his texts in
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): order to set him
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): up for a crime. so let's listen to that
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): SOT, this is SOT 2, I believe, mystery producer.
Countries tend to
Speaker 58: become more authoritarian in wartime. It's just the nature of war. People are dying. The stakes are
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): high. People's emotions have risen to a very high point, a crescendo. And so there's much less tolerance for any kind of dissent.
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): In the homeland, the irony, of course, is the United States fights wars on behalf of freedom, but there's always less of
it here
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): in our country during war. There's no justification for your government, which you own, you're a shareholder in it, you pay for it, to be violating your privacy like this. But it happens all the time. And in fact, one of the reasons that CIA or people within CIA, just to be clear, it's a huge, sprawling, disconnected agency. What
it does in a
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): specific case doesn't represent what everybody in the building thinks. but there are
some people
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): People who are mad at me for my views about Israel. And they have some latitude. And one of the reasons they pass on criminal complaints, in effect, to law enforcement is to justify warrants for spying on Americans. So that is an absolutely real thing. But the main reason they do it is to leak the existence of the investigation, such as it is.
to
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): the media and then humiliate and terrify the subjects of this op. And that's, of course, happened to me repeatedly.
Speaker 60: Okay. So this came in a tweet,
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): right, that basically said when you find out that the CIA is
–
Speaker 62: monitoring your texts in an attempt to... What was the exact language in an attempt to set you up? In an
Speaker 63: attempt to make some kind of
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): criminal referral against him because they don't like his views on Israel or something to that effect.
So a
Speaker 64: couple of things about this before we get to what
to
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): think about this. Tucker,
Speaker 65: obviously, there was an incident...
Speaker 65: Was it last year, the
FISA
Speaker 66: incident, or was it? No,
that
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): was 2021. 2021. That's right. It was 2021. Okay. So he was attempting to arrange
Speaker 27: an interview with Putin, which he didn't ultimately get. But this is while he was
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): still on Fox in 2021. Yeah. Putin interview was later after he had launched his independent media venture.
Speaker 7: Right, right. And almost immediately after
he made the
Speaker 7: I made a phone call to somebody in the Russian government.
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): There was an Axios story, essentially saying, you know, confirmed Tucker Carlson had contact with somebody in
the
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): uh, in the Russian government. So that whole
Speaker 68: business about the FISA, he claimed that he'd been monitored by FISA. There was a lot of, there were a lot of people who were very skeptical of that. I think it ultimately
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): turned out to be true. They weren't listening to him per se. They were probably listening, uh, to,
uh, whoever
Speaker 69: was on the other end of that call. Um,
and so
Speaker 70: incidentally could have gotten swept up into whatever surveillance,
Speaker 71: uh,
Speaker 69: Yeah.
Speaker 71: Protocol was in effect to monitor the Russian state actors. Yeah.
Speaker 7: Well, it was FISA. And the
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): problem is that it's become too easy to access FISA and to unmask people and do all this all kinds of other stuff, which is why the fact that it was leaked
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): so quickly to the to the media became ridiculous.
you
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): know it was a little bit of a scandal right
Speaker 7: it's it's it's essentially somebody in the intelligence community um leaking news to somebody in the press about tucker having contact with uh russians
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): this story seems to be a little bit different michael like what's your understanding of exactly what happened here i
don't have a great
Speaker 72: understanding of exactly what happened because look i mean
Speaker 72: I
Speaker 10: currently have some reason to doubt the accuracy with which Tucker is currently perceiving reality on a variety of different fronts.
So not
Speaker 10: that I would just discount what he's saying here totally right off the bat. Like there might be some kernel of truth to it.
I just think that
Speaker 10: Tucker has been in such an epistemic free fall lately.
where
Speaker 10: especially since he launched his new media venture and
it's
Speaker 11: kind of just accelerated ever since he's not bound by any kind of like guardrails of like a traditional conception of
Speaker 10: facts and evidence such that it's less and less tenable for me to just take a total face value whatever he's relaying
so I
I
Speaker 10: mean, if we do take it at face value, what he seems to be saying is that he was in communication with people
Speaker 11: in Iran prior
to the
Speaker 11: war being launched and
that this was
Speaker 11: picked up on by the CIA or monitored and the CIA made
some sort of
Speaker 11: criminal referral. I'm not sure what process that would necessarily entail, but there was some criminal referral allegedly made or he was allegedly told.
Speaker 11: And he's potentially now going
Speaker 74: to be accused of some sort of subversion or treason or something like that.
Speaker 75: I've seen multiple
Speaker 76: variants. Some people say it's a Farrah charge. Some people say it's some sort of like aiding and abetting the enemy. This is just
Speaker 48: people speculating based on how he told it.
Speaker 1: Right, which is one of the weird things about this. Well, it's not weird. It's totally
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): weird.
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): standard now for how media works um the the reason i brought up the faiza thing before is is that yes it did ultimately turn out that that was true
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): uh and the immediate speculation turned out to be um most of it turned out to be uh incorrect but as you say like tucker's
Speaker 77 (lower-pitched voice): been he hasn't
uh
Speaker 77 (lower-pitched voice): exactly been behaving like somebody who was raised in the litigation sensitive
Speaker 68: sensitive um corporate media uh lately um let's look at a couple of clips that what one
Speaker 10: second though just i
mean i
Speaker 10: think this is this is useful context because here's how tucker described what went on in the 2021
incident he said
Speaker 10: and this was him on fox he
said
He told
Speaker 11: his audience on Fox, quote, the Biden administration is spying on us. We have confirmed that.
Now, if you
Speaker 11: notice, he could easily say in theory that the Trump administration is spying on me or potentially trying to frame
Speaker 78: me for some kind of criminal offense. And he does claim that he's potentially being framed. That was what he wrote in the initial tweet that put out the video. But it's always he's he's he does the same routine now
Speaker 10: that he always does, especially vis-a-vis Trump in this Iran war.
Speaker 10: which is he always tries to mysteriously exempt Trump from the criticism that he appears to be leveling, which he aims at other sort of nefarious actors that are surrounding Trump and leading him
Speaker 46: astray.
Speaker 46: Right. So whereas, you know, when this happened, when some version of this happened five years ago, he had no problem directly blaming Joe Biden and the Biden
Speaker 49: administration and making a very clear cut political point out of it. Now it goes into this whole thing where he's
Speaker 78: trying what he's been trying to do because he doesn't like the Iran war, I think justifiably so. But what he's been trying to do is displace any responsibility for the initiation
Speaker 79: of the Iran war off of Trump entirely and solely onto Israel.
And and
Speaker 79: the CIA.
And
Speaker 79: the CIA or like other like deep state actors
Speaker 78: who are working in concert with Israel. OK, so that's not me saying that Israel has no role whatsoever in why this war was launched. It's just noting that there's this caricature or overwrought cartoon version of Israel that Tucker and people of a similar inclination
have been
Speaker 78: myopically fixating on in
lieu of
Speaker 78: actually doing what they know they can't do.
And
Speaker 79: or at least they can't do and remain in good standing with Trump, which is that they can't actually direct their critique at him. So I think this is a continuation
Speaker 78: of this like obfuscatory routine he's been doing where.
The commander in
Speaker 78: chief somehow has no agency for launching the war that Tucker claims is this apocalyptic disaster. So this is just kind of like a side plot in that
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): narrative.
Speaker 81: Yeah. And.
- Well,
Speaker 81: we'll get
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): to this in a second. There was an amazing sort of galvanizing reaction by everybody in the podcast community when he did this. But let's share a couple of the clips of the things that you're talking about. Do we have Tucker Pizzagate,
mystery
Speaker 82: producer,
Speaker 83: or Tucker Demons? Here we go.
- So how do
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): we assess it? Well, that's gonna take an awfully long
time.
Most
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): people don't have the time. So
we thought
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): it would be interesting just to start with a very narrow slice of the material. And that's the emails and texts that we can be pretty sure were sent from or to Jeffrey Epstein that pertain to the question of food, specifically pizza.
And that
Speaker 59 (lower-pitched voice): caught our attention immediately. Pizza, people talking about pizza, adults talking about pizza and pizza parties. Now, why did that catch our attention? Of course, because it evoked memories of this semi-forgotten story from about 10 years ago known as Pizzagate. So
just to be clear,
Speaker 79: okay, so why is this
Speaker 10: notable and why would this cause me to have certain doubts as
to the
Speaker 10: reliability of how he's perceiving current events?
Yeah.
He and
Speaker 10: his team apparently decided that the most prudent research methodology for them to adopt in explaining to their giant audience the nature and significance of this latest round of quote-unquote Epstein files was to, first and foremost, focus on pizza. I mean, focus on various foodstuffs that they could eat.
Speaker 10: Input into the DOJ search bar and then impute some kind of sinister meaning to. There are lots of potentially viable methodological routes one could have taken to research this, you know, these millions of Epstein files. Right. And, you know, I, for
Speaker 56: example, want to find certain prosecution memos and
Speaker 46: there's other stuff.
But
Speaker 46: if your immediate instinct was to just say pizza, pizza, pizza, let's find pizza parties and potentially other food items that we could connect to pizza and then connect back 10 years in the past to the Pizzagate narrative, that tells me there's something like epistemically fundamentally flawed in your whole framework
Speaker 55: for processing information.
Speaker 84: Yeah.
-
Speaker 85: Go ahead.
Speaker 84: Yeah, so that's a red flag
Speaker 85: to say the least.
-
Speaker 86: And he's not the only person in the podcast universe who's doing this. It's like
all over the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): place. Everyone from Bill Maher to Crystal and Sagar at breaking points, they kind of somewhat surprisingly endorsed Pizzagate
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): uh in a show a little bit ago um but let's take a look at tucker demons
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): as well because this is another sort of linguistic constant um of this period you think
you
Speaker 88: were attacked by a demon and
i have to
Speaker 88: tell you like a lot of people mock this they roll their eyes but i look at like what happened to charlie what happened in the wake of charlie
What
Speaker 88: happened at the Ascension School in Minneapolis, where that man went in there and shot a bunch of little children praying at their church school?
And I
Speaker 88: challenge
Speaker 89: anyone to tell me there aren't demons among us.
Well, I never
Speaker 90: thought there were. I thought it was, I thought the whole thing was like bizarre. So what happened? Because
Speaker 91: like culturally, I'm just not from a world where people are attacked by demons. And
in fact, when
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): it happened the next morning, when I saw the blood on my sheets, I was like...
I
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): actually called someone who works for me who's a very sincere, lifelong evangelical, and I'm like,
"Have you ever heard of this?"
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): And she's like, "Oh yeah, it happens all the time." I was like,
"What?" Not to
Speaker 93: Episcopalians, it doesn't. -
Stuff it
Speaker 94: down. - Yeah, no, it was, well, yeah, I mean,
Speaker 93: I'm not embarrassed at all, and I don't care if I'm mocked. Don't get anything out of making this up, and I'm not
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): making it up. - But
Speaker 96: what happened?
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): - I had this crazy experience where I was in the truck with someone coming back from quail hunting,
and I
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): had all of a sudden this, we were talking about someone I despise.
And all
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): of a sudden, I had this crazy empathy for the person, like really intense empathy, like it could understand why this person was doing these horrible things. And
I said to the
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): person, this is a family dispute, right? So I said
to the
Speaker 95 (lower-pitched voice): person, maybe my brother, and I said, I think
I know
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): what's happening here. This person feels this way, that way, this way. And my brother goes, how did you know that?
I said I
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): don't know it just like and my brother goes I think like God is like speaking through you or something and I felt total true empathy for this person I truly hate it
was like the
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): craziest thing has ever happened to me I have no idea where it came from I was like I think that's from God like there's no way you could say well that's kind of wild so then I get home we have this huge dinner party which we always have dinner parties and I forget about it I'm telling you this because they're twins the one leads to the other I had this thing profound experience with God like profound
and
Speaker 92 (lower-pitched voice): beautiful and unexpected and
Speaker 97: then i go to bed with my wife and four dogs who sleep in the bed my wife said
Speaker 98: four children all right my dogs
Speaker 99: we get
it uh so in
Speaker 99: other words he he ends up going on to explain how he woke up in the middle of the night and felt like he couldn't breathe and
And
Speaker 99: he goes outside and he wanders around. He finally regains his composure, but then he realized he has scratch marks that are bleeding.
And his
Speaker 10: conclusion is that he was attacked by a literal demon who entered from the metaphysical realm into the physical realm, scratched him even as he was all already in the habit of sleeping in bed with several hunting dogs
where,
Speaker 10: But that apparently did not occur to him as a plausible explanation for why it is that he got these scratches while he was sleeping in bed.
And he's
Speaker 10: very earnest about this. I had heard about this story even prior to him debuting it publicly. And from everything I can gather, he like earnestly believes it. So I'm just going to take
him at his
Speaker 10: word and that he earnestly believes this stuff and he believes God is speaking through him. And he's he's had like some major religious epiphany.
Speaker 10: and he now, I guess, styles himself as some sort of prophet through whom God is communicating to the world
and
Speaker 100: giving him all these revelatory insights. And
by the
Speaker 100: way,
Speaker 101: he's not the only person who's got this issue. There are lots of politicians, some of them in the government, some of them in foreign governments,
Speaker 102: but whatever. No, I'm not
Speaker 103: just saying, but this
Speaker 49: all adds up to a collapse in whatever epistemic guardrails of Tucker's
Speaker 49: that I could
Speaker 79: perceive prior to, like, the past couple years. Because I was a semi-regular guest on his show. I've known him personally. Always
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): got along with him. I like Tucker. Yeah, yeah, yeah. I still do. Yeah, I don't have any personal dislike for him at all. I'm just saying that, you know, if
this is going to be
Speaker 49: an issue of public concern, right, that deals with him, and he's going to exert the political influence that he does, I simply cannot...
Speaker 49: Just credulously accept every sort of blinkered theory that he decides to blurt out as presumptively reliable, given what I know about his precipitous decline in
Speaker 19: like knowledge production standards.
Speaker 19: And also
Speaker 106: his... Minus five for the academic jargon there. Sorry, sorry,
Speaker 107: sorry, sorry, sorry, sorry. That's okay, that's all right. I'll sit and time out. Say five Hail Marys after the show. But anyway, go ahead.
Speaker 108: Okay, how about our fathers? Because I am
Speaker 109 (lower-pitched voice): Irish, so I'll be wracked with guilt that I'll have to go to the confessional to absolve myself
Speaker 110: of. But anyway, so like, yeah, that's the bottom
Speaker 79: line in that I just can't take, I can't just...
Speaker 79: instinctively trust anything in terms of the accuracy of how he's portraying it at this point. And I had another experience with
Speaker 100: him over the summer where I ran to a brick wall with him over Epstein because he had this guy on his show for three hours, Daryl Cooper, who he had rush over to do an emergency Epstein podcast and tell millions of people what they should know about Epstein, like an introductory
Speaker 78: primer on Epstein. It was like one sentence after the next of just total nonsensical...
Speaker 78: hysteria fomenting lunacy and
like i just
Speaker 78: couldn't like get through to him so i kind of just gave up after a while and but now i feel like things have a little bit
Speaker 46: come to a head where like
he's one of the major
Speaker 111: people forming political perceptions around like the iran war trump's
Speaker 99: culpability or lack thereof in the war the role of israel in the war and then you tie in this new little um
Speaker 99: rabbit
Speaker 10: hole that we're on where he potentially is also somehow involved in having been spied on by the FBI because he's an Israel critic or because he's too critical of the war etc etc like now I have to like set aside whatever personal affinity
that I
Speaker 10: did once have for him and still do on some level and just explain why it is that I feel like people should be rationally doubtful
Speaker 10: about the, about how, how seriously we can take anything that he's been saying at this point, absent, like corroborating
Speaker 78: evidence or some other form of substantiation, which he could maybe provide at some point, but as of now he hasn't.
And or
Speaker 112: what, what will come out if there is, you know, if there
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): are actual charges, we'll find out what it is that they're, they're setting them up for if they are indeed. But it's funny that you
Speaker 113: mentioned
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): guilt and.
I
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): had only just started to come to grips with some lingering guilt that I felt about an undercover assignment I did a gazillion years ago where I went and lived as a member of an apocalyptic church.
uh
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): in san antonio um yeah yeah i was in john haggie's church which is very relevant to the current
Speaker 114: moment because he was basically like the um the main figure like cornerstone
Speaker 115: church or
Speaker 116: something cornerstone i
was a
Speaker 116: member of cornerstone for six months and um what six months yeah six months i lived on there in san antonio it's this
Speaker 117: is in the book the great derangement uh that i wrote
Speaker 117: Yeah, I have a vague memory of this, but I don't think I ever read that particular
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): book.
Speaker 7: Well, you're 20 years younger than me, so it makes sense. It was a while ago, but one
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): of the things that we did at Cornerstone, there was a retreat for all the young men in the church, and we had to go basically to this church.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): camp where there were segregated dorms and everything. We were taught that each of us had demons inside of us and we had to go through these exercises where we vomited demons into bags. They
Speaker 7: handed out paper bags
Speaker 68: to all of us. I was sitting...
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Obviously, it was the old cliché
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): you know New York savvy writer picking on the yokels story right and I I was probably meaner than I had to be when I wrote up what
Speaker 119: actually happened where did
Speaker 120: where was this written up for was it written for for the book specifically or did it appear someplace
Speaker 121: else in the book and it was in Rolling Stone also um and and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): you know later on I uh you know the the book isn't really all that mean actually I it ended up being the
the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): I was significantly muted by the fact that I felt kind of bad for a lot of the people in the church and they were mostly really nice people. It's just that some of the folks in the church itself were pretty manipulative and they were putting stuff over on people. But just as I was getting to the point where I was feeling guilty for picking on
people about
you
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): know, believing in demons and trying to vomit demons into bags. It's back. Like everybody's talking about demons. Demonology
Speaker 122: is like now one of the
Speaker 99: main currencies of the online media ecosystem. Meaning if you want, if you want to get algorithmically boosted, one thing you can definitely do is unveil this whole worldview around the ever presence of demons and,
Speaker 99: You know,
I
Speaker 49: think there might be a difference you could posit between people who believe in demons as like a metaphor or like
Speaker 10: demons are just another way of like pointing to our sins or something like that.
Meaning a sort of a
Speaker 10: lighter version
of belief
Speaker 10: in demons and attributing a specific like
Speaker 123: physical intercession in the material universe
to.
Speaker 123: to a demon attacking you and attributing a particular injury that you were
sustained to an
Speaker 49: attack by a demon. Like that to me is like a different level of belief that where I wouldn't, whereas the people who just kind of like, because it is sort of a tentative Christian belief writ large, let's say to generalize a bit, that like demons on some level exist in the universe, right?
And another to
Speaker 49: claim some kind of direct personal interaction
Speaker 79: with or victimization by demons.
Speaker 79: physically a demon which like puts you front and center
Speaker 10: and yeah you you you tie that in with tucker believing that like god speaks through
him that's
Speaker 10: like a weird sort of monomania thing or
Speaker 79: megalomaniacal thing that goes pretty far beyond just this generic belief in
Speaker 56: demons perhaps being present
Speaker 124: right we're not talking about dostoevsky
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): who writing about
you
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): know writing the book the demons right uh which is sometimes called the possessed uh where he was generally talking in a christian sense about how uh and tolstoy did this too all russian writers eventually come around and talk telling you that the devil is real and and you know it's it's a it's a physical thing but here when you start talking about it being
Speaker 1: in your bed and scratching you or being something that you lose weight when you vomited into a
Speaker 1: bag which is one of the things that they told us like uh
Speaker 39: then then it gets to to silliness and it's all over the place now and uh in this like their demonology is part of this whole explanation
Speaker 86: of what's happening in the middle east and you know alex jones saying
Speaker 3: the
Speaker 125: devil is real demons are real like that that was part of his argument with um with jimmy door there yeah you know
Speaker 48: on the on On the previous episode, we talked about some of the potential
Speaker 48: parallels
Speaker 10: between the Epstein story and the satanic panic daycare craze story of the eighties. And if you go back and read around about like what the cultural climate at the time, it was, you know, these, these mass market bestselling books like, um,
And like books
Speaker 10: you could get, you could get on like the checkout line at the grocery store or something, which were incredibly popular, were oftentimes about demonology and how they intersected with like therapy. And there was one book, I can't remember, I can't recall the name now, but there's a book where about like basically a therapist somehow exercising a demon from one of his patients. And like, this was just very commercially
popular in
Speaker 10: the 1980s and it like kind of,
it
Speaker 10: contributed to the cultural firmament
Speaker 126: at the time. You're right. There was a book that was extraordinarily popular. Yeah, like
Speaker 48: shockingly popular. And I think I made it to a movie and stuff. I can't recall the name off the top of my head. Yeah. But I see something...
And
Speaker 49: now it gets happening now, which
is why
Speaker 49: us talking about Tucker here isn't just arbitrary in terms
of
Speaker 10: how it could relate to the overall theme that we're talking about, which is like this podcast versus traditional media question, which is worse, et cetera, because I think one reason one one thing that really is polluting.
The
Speaker 10: podcast-oriented media or the online media circuit is this bizarre explosion of algorithmic incentivization around playing up these quasi-mystical explanations for things. Totally. Demons. Chucker, in that same video where he talks about the demon attack, goes on to say that he views UFOs because he has a long-standing interest in UFOs, but now he's concluded that UFOs such as they
Speaker 129: exist are like spiritual beings from another...
you
Speaker 110: know dimension right um so it's it's stuff like that and like this stuff just gets
Speaker 79: this stuff like people eat this stuff up they love it and it forms their worldview and then that that
Speaker 10: creates the feedback loop where if because the online media is so responsive to like audience sentiment they just
give the
Speaker 78: people what they want
And
Speaker 78: and we're
Speaker 131: going to argue about this later, but I would one of the things I'm going to argue is that
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the mainstream press is partially responsible for this because they started legitimizing the concept of dot connecting as a as a form of analysis. Right. Just to answer this question here from D. Stunk guys, are you saying that what is going on right now in the world is not a battle of good versus evil question, question, question?
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): being serious now um i might
be saying
Speaker 7: that i'm certainly saying that i i don't think physical demons are involved in the picture um and if they are like like
i guess
Speaker 86: this gets to the larger
Speaker 101: question of what what is this program you
Speaker 132: know we're not
Speaker 101: going to give you
Speaker 86: wild theories about things um we're we may not even get to the issue of
whether
Speaker 68: or not we think there is
good versus
Speaker 68: I'm not even sure that that's our job. But one of the things I think we both
Speaker 5: believe is that
most of
Speaker 5: what we see out there is a lot more complicated than is being represented in podcasts, right?
Speaker 69: I will answer
Speaker 79: that question. I am saying I'll declare it right now. I am saying that I reject that the world is fundamentally a battle of
Speaker 123: good versus evil. I think that's a totally infantile way of looking at the world.
Speaker 123: world yes with all its complexities complexities and subtleties now if you have a worldview whether religious or otherwise which tells you that everything must be sorted into this paradigm of good versus evil okay you're entitled to have that but i'm not going to affirm that because i don't believe that okay i think that's i think these comforting tales of good versus evil or black you know everything is morally black or white those are the kind of tales that you tell little children
Speaker 123: who lack the cognitive capacity to apprehend moral subtlety
or
Speaker 49: like gradations in morality, right? So you tell them what? A fairy tale about the three little pigs versus the big bad wolf. That's something they can understand.
Speaker 10: But then hopefully once they develop more adult reasoning capacities, they can come to appreciate how the scope of human experience doesn't
Speaker 123: necessarily lend itself to these hyper-reductive
ideas
Speaker 49: impressions of good versus evil and then just like projecting that onto everything that happens in the world war political scandal
Speaker 79: whatever i think that's totally asinine so i am willing to give
a firm
Speaker 79: statement on that because i think that's a that that's
a
Speaker 49: cognitive distortion that i think just warps how people process information about the world around them
yeah i would
Speaker 133: answer that a little answer that a little differently like um i think I
don't know.
The
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): whole question of good and evil, and how that's experienced in people and everybody's capacity for the one or the other.
These
Speaker 121: sort of complex metaphysical questions, I probably wouldn't even ever share what I actually
Speaker 68: think about that with the public, but in terms of the news and
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): how people consume
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): uh
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): information about world events you're absolutely right that one of the things that's happened in recent years
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): is that all of the gradations uh have been washed out of uh almost
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): every subject and you
know i i
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): think this is originally one of the complaints about mainly about the sort of woke left but
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): it's now on on all sides which is that everything has become
uh
you
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): know, this sort of black and white,
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): all good, all bad, you know, people are one or the other, right?
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): This is one of the things that was upsetting to me about how the digital censorship system works. They would identify people as inherently misinformative.
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): um as opposed to the things that they say right uh and so they would be like thrown in you know the de-amplification bin when people have the everybody has the capacity to be deceptive right uh or to tell
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): the truth and that's what i really worry about right now is this is this
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): everybody retreating into these corners people are all one thing or the other um you know
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): issues
Speaker 65: are simple right there there's good versus bad black versus white like i don't know yeah you
Speaker 108: know like when the war when the war in ukraine was launched february 2022 it was emphatically proclaimed by every think tanker
Speaker 49: and like quote unquote mainstream media figure that we were all morally obliged to view that conflict as fundamentally a
Speaker 49: This cosmic battle between good and evil, meaning Putin was evil, Zelensky and Ukraine were good. Now, in my rejecting that binary, I'm
Speaker 10: not therefore condoning or excusing in any way Putin's action.
And I'm
Speaker 10: not even precluding myself from
Speaker 79: elucidating ways in which I would find his actions to be condemnable.
But
Speaker 79: I'm still going to reject that framework because it's so ludicrously oversimplified that in no way could it possibly be conducive to developing a rational understanding of the causes and nature of that conflict.
And a
Speaker 79: similar prism gets applied, you're right, to so much stuff in recent times, especially.
And I think maybe the
Speaker 79: alternative media on some level
Speaker 134: contributes to
Speaker 79: that. I don't know that I could maybe attribute it
Speaker 79: more or less to the mainstream versus alternative media maybe it's like a mixed bag but whatever the contributors i i maintain that it is a uh a fairly infantile way of looking at at the world especially if you're a journalist right i mean how could you do your journalistic how could you do any issue journalistic justice let's say if you go into it presupposing that like one side is like fully evil and one side is fully
good
I
Speaker 79: mean, maybe if you want to, if you want to create a morality tale out of it or a fairy tale that you can then tell to children, then that might be a more legitimate approach. But
Speaker 56: journalistically, meaning you're
trying to
Speaker 56: best apprehend and then chronicle the truth for like historical
Speaker 10: posterity or for your readers. I just don't see how that binary could possibly lend itself to a bona fide
Speaker 135: journalistic inquiry. No,
I
Speaker 7: mean...
Speaker 7: that's the opposite of what we were taught to do right uh or at least what i was i don't know i mean i'm again i'm older than you but uh you know we
Speaker 86: were always taught talk to as many people as you can there's gonna be you know seven
Speaker 1: people who were gonna say one thing they're gonna be fine people who say another thing but there might be two people who are the most convincing um you
The
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): challenge is sifting through all that. It's never just one or the other and the thing that's corrupted a
lot of
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): media organizations is they've They've sort of pre-determined This is what more that whole moral clarity journalism thing that drove me nuts was was just basically pre-deciding which sources are wrong about you
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): putting them in a certain category. We don't have to quote them because they're always wrong, right? We don't have to print their denials. We don't have to print their explanations. But now that happens on all sides. And it's a disservice
Speaker 86: to everybody because sometimes the people you don't like are right. And sometimes the people that you do like are wrong. And that's part of
Speaker 121: being a grownup is learning that stuff. But we're raising...
Speaker 121: you know,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): hyper-emotional, binary-thinking children, basically. I don't know. I mean, I know that's a horrible
Speaker 136 (lower-pitched voice): thing to say, but it feels like that's what we're actually doing at the moment. Especially,
I
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): mean, obviously all this was turbocharged with Trump being like this organizing principle of everybody's daily consciousness, where like your position relative to him
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): Meaning your moral outlook on him as positive or negative, like defines the rest of your worldview and
Speaker 10: like inflects the rest of every belief that you hold, which is something that I've always tried to resist. I
mean, my view on
Speaker 10: Trump is more antagonistic in the second term than even it was in the first part term. But in the first term, no, I did think that it was
Speaker 49: worthwhile to.
Speaker 49: focusing by and large on the hysterical, overwrought sort of liberal narratives that were generated in
Speaker 56: reaction to Trump, Russiagate being foremost amongst them, because that was that actually had a lot of adverse effects on a whole variety of things, including his foreign
Speaker 10: policy. But
then, you
Speaker 10: know, now Epstein is
like,
has
Speaker 10: supplanted Russiagate,
Speaker 79: right, as the predominant second-term oppositional narrative against Trump. And even now, with my being much more
sort of
Speaker 79: pessimistic or ominous or even oftentimes disturbed about what the second-term Trump phenomenon is, I'm
Speaker 46: still...
Speaker 46: not going to just arbitrarily say to myself, gee, because it
Speaker 79: could somehow incidentally redound to the political advantage of Trump that I'm showing why the main oppositional narrative against him is flawed. I'm therefore not going to do like the journalistic interrogation of it that I would otherwise be disposed to do because I have this higher principle that I'm following, which is antipathy to Trump. Like that's never
Speaker 55: been my
Speaker 55: lodestar let's say um but i feel like lots of people whether just you just talk about ordinary citizens people on the internet or or journalists
feel i i
Speaker 55: really get the strong impression that they it never even occurs to them to sort of like reason about things at that level it's always just like what is their initial emotional
Speaker 78: reaction and then like what what beliefs then flow from that and you know not to be too highfalutin about it but like if you want to
do a
Speaker 78: little bit more of refined reasoning you have to kind of think about things with a
Speaker 137: little bit more of detachment especially for journalists
Speaker 138: yeah no the thing i used to like about journalists is that they they didn't give
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): a shit about uh they they were totally detached about it and you if you
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): hung out in a newsroom it was like hanging out at a comedy club um they joked about everything and the only thing that they really cared about
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): was is this writer is this
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): is it incorrect you know because that was their careers if they if they screwed it up you talk about Trump the the thing that drove me nuts about the the press starting in 2016 and I used to talk about this with Walter also
but was the
And you
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): could only explain his rise in one way. They would only like if you said something other than it was a manifestation of white supremacy, then people would start to say that you're.
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): you know, a Trump supporter or whatever it was. And then they use that as a disciplinary method, right? Which is-
Speaker 139: Or your anti-anti-Trump, remember that? Anti-anti-Trump, there was a whole-
Speaker 49: That was declared to be this nefarious little cohort within the media where these ideological
Speaker 10: traitors, people who had been perceived as somewhat more progressive or left-wing of some kind-
had
Speaker 10: given over to their contrarianism and now we're not necessarily pro-Trump overtly, but anti-Trump because they were critical of Russiagate or they were critical of like... Oh, were you in that story? I was. I mean, there was like a vanity... I don't know if you remember this. Yeah, I think... John
Speaker 140: Chait did it, I think.
Speaker 10: There was one in Vanity Fair by James Wolcott, I remember. Oh,
Speaker 141: Wolcott did it too? Yeah,
Speaker 10: yeah. That's the one that I recall. I think Jonathan Chait did it. Yeah, I think I remember the Jonathan Chait one
too.
But
Speaker 10: yeah, but they were trying to like just will into existence this
Speaker 49: clique of anti-anti-Trump people to try to like define whatever commonalities
Speaker 56: existed between them in terms of like temperament or some kind of political
Speaker 10: tendency or whatever.
But it was
Speaker 10: all ultimately in relation to Trump. So like that's what defined you, right? So if you didn't have the proper moral comportment vis-a-vis
Trump,
Speaker 70: then you were...
Speaker 70: inundated with these, you know, accusations of some kind of grave failure.
You
Speaker 142: were a denialist. They came up with all these words for it. But
now
Speaker 1: they're doing the same thing, as you say, with the Epstein story. And there was an amazing example of it over this weekend.
Speaker 86: Can we see SOT 5? This is Conan
Speaker 143: O'Brien at the Oscars. Yeah.
Speaker 143: Just a barrel of laughs, Conan.
So I have people who
Speaker 144: feed me
Speaker 100: stuff whenever they see
like a
Speaker 100: capricious reference to pedophiles nowadays
because I
Speaker 100: wasn't sitting there watching the Oscars opening monologue. And yet somebody
Speaker 109 (lower-pitched voice): informed me, okay, time to take a drink. Of course, Conan, like within the first five minutes
did a
Speaker 109 (lower-pitched voice): such and such joke.
Here we
Speaker 146: go.
Speaker 145: It's
the
Speaker 146: first time since 2012 that's the first time
Speaker 146: First time since 2012
Speaker 147: that there are no British actors nominated for Best Actor or Best Actress.
Speaker 148: Yeah, British spokespersons said, "Yeah, well at least we arrest our pedophiles."
Speaker 149: So, we got
that going for you.
Speaker 150: So, okay, okay trolls, all you folks who came in here to yell at us
Speaker 151: about this shit.
Speaker 151: What the fuck are we talking about? What pedophiles? But
Speaker 152: then, so, like, I mean, look, I'm fine with the most morbid, shocking,
Speaker 10: grotesque humor imaginable. Like, I mean, I enjoy that. That's some of the only humor that I do enjoy. However, this wasn't even funny, for
one thing. And
Speaker 46: second of all...
If it
Speaker 46: can't justify be justified simply on the grounds of being funny, you then have to wonder, OK, so, like, what
is
Speaker 49: this communicating to however many people still watch the Oscars or we'll see a clip later or what have you? Well, it's conveying
Speaker 46: that, like, gee, there's something really terrible going on in the United States because compared to England or compared to Britain.
Speaker 46: we're going soft on our pedophile problem. Whereas at least they will arrest a couple of Epstein connected pedophiles. So
obviously
Speaker 111: that's a reference to Prince Andrew and Peter Mendelsohn who were arrested on these totally concocted pretextual charges that had nothing to do with any sex crime at all, but obviously were catalyzed or the impetus for them was the public uproar over
Speaker 56: their perceived connections to this most notorious pedophile in human history. Um...
Speaker 56: And for people who don't know this, they've
Speaker 51: probably seen the
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): picture of Lord Peter Mandelson in his tighty-whities in Jeffrey Epstein's apartment in Paris. But I don't know, Michael, how many people do, what percentage of Americans do you think know
that Lord
Speaker 153: Peter Mandelson is gay? 100, for sure.
No, I
Speaker 154: mean,
Speaker 46: virtually none, which is why. And then so another thing that they do is they put out those they put out images. So
Speaker 10: people don't even read headlines. Oftentimes they'll look at just whatever the image is that they're blasted into their awareness. Right. And so the DOJ had this practice that they adopted after acceding to these demands that were made by the
Speaker 129: so-called victims and their lawyers who were frantically charged.
arguing
Speaker 129: in federal court for months prior to this most recent Epstein document
Speaker 10: production that the DOJ be compelled to impose this most sweeping possible redactions imaginable, pretty much. So the same people who, on the one hand, were going around sloganeering saying, release the Epstein files, meaning the so-called victims and their lawyers, they were behind the scenes impressing on federal judges how urgently necessary it was that the DOJ be compelled
to
Speaker 49: ensure that the fewest possible Epstein files were actually released or that the greatest quantity of Epstein files were marred with all these totally superfluous redactions.
But one thing that the
Speaker 49: DOJ ended
Speaker 42: up doing at the direction of these lawyers was say, okay, we are going to presumptively treat each and every woman who is depicted in some photo or image as a victim,
even if
Speaker 10: there's no claim
that
Speaker 10: they were even victimized, much less that any claimed victimization had actually been investigated whatsoever for veracity or credibility. It's just any woman, with the exception of Ghislaine Maxwell, is going to be considered a victim, and therefore their facial images, facial imagery, which is what Todd Blanche, the deputy attorney general, said, that's going to be presumptively redacted, whereas every man, presumptively
Speaker 42: unredacted. So you have these absurd situations where Peter Mandelson, who is gay...
is in a
Speaker 42: photo with some woman or female whose face is presumptively blacked out. And yeah, he's in his like
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): bathrobe
Speaker 156: or something. She's a survivor. So she's
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): a survivor. Again, even if she never even claimed survivorhood, survivorship, whatever you want, whatever the noun is. And so what does that convey to the untrained eye? Yeah.
well
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): no that woman's a victim of something and
Speaker 42: peter mandelson either victimized her or was complicit in enabling her victimization right right i
Speaker 158: mean i'm sure one could make the argument that it didn't make her feel comfortable to be there with a dude in his underwear i there's an argument for that but uh shouldn't you ask
Speaker 159: her shouldn't
Speaker 160: you ask her shouldn't she be asked yeah
Speaker 159: i think absolutely yeah um for sure uh but
For
Speaker 159: those who
Speaker 86: were saying, like, there were people talking about, well, what about Jimmy Savile, right? He's a famous British DJ who, after his death,
Speaker 161: there was this avalanche of sex abuse allegations, and police essentially concluded that he was a...
Speaker 161: Serial sex offender.
Speaker 162: Well, okay that that does happen, but these people are alive and
Speaker 113: there there's no evidence that they're pedophiles beyond the fact that that They appear in this file
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): now that doesn't mean that Lord Peter Mandelson didn't do something wrong right there there might be
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): you
know
It
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): looks like some of those communications are at least suspicious in terms of sharing maybe financial information.
Speaker 163: I know, but
Speaker 111: that charge in the UK or in England... Oh, no, the law is totally, yeah. Yeah, it's like
Speaker 10: misconduct in public office. It's
like a
Speaker 10: catch-all charge. It's like the equivalent of, I don't know, a distortively conduct charge, which can just sweep up virtually anything if you annoy a cop. Like, if you annoy a cop...
he doesn't
Speaker 10: even have to charge you with anything that is specifically tailored to what you did. He could just say it's this
Speaker 129: early conduct or obstruction or like, like in New York city, they have a charge called obstruction of governmental administration.
Speaker 164: Yeah. OGA. Yeah.
Speaker 10: Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Which is like, it just mean anything. Right. So that's pretty much the equivalent of what this charge is in the UK that they, they charge both
or they
Speaker 129: arrested anyway, both Mandelson and Prince Andrew.
Speaker 165: Yeah. But
Speaker 129: like, but then like my, but my problem with this Conan,
Speaker 46: wise crack is okay number one it's not funny so like you can't even justify it on that grounds but number two it
is still it is
Speaker 46: it does contribute to this idea that
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): we're in the throes of this massive pedophilia crisis where all the pedophiles are
Speaker 46: being allowed to run free with impunity and therefore the usa better up its game and match what our colleagues in the uk have been
doing to
Speaker 46: hold the pedophiles to account right which is just like a totally
warped
Speaker 46: perception to be encouraging about like, what's actually going on here.
Speaker 159: What was the, what did do he has? Remember Neil Patrick Harris? What did he say about
Speaker 65: Glenn at the Oscars? Remember he said something totally, totally.
Speaker 166: Oh, so you mean like in 2013 or something or yeah. Yeah.
Speaker 167: When citizen four one, he
Speaker 168 (lower-pitched voice): said Edward Snowden couldn't be there for some treason. Uh, and that was the joke. Um, but
Speaker 169: like,
This
Speaker 169: is worse. There was a time when you couldn't go on television and just call somebody a pedophile.
Speaker 123: But he's not calling anybody individually a pedophile. He's just gesturing toward this pedophile epidemic. He kind
Speaker 170: of is. If I were Mandelson and Prince Andrew. Oh, that's
Speaker 171: right. I was thinking of Americans. Yeah, he's definitely calling those two pedophiles. Right? So, yeah, I mean...
I
Speaker 46: mean, I think you see, but what he's pretty much, you know, not so subtly intimating is that
Speaker 10: this pedophile impunity is being, is the result of Donald Trump, right? Like, that's always
the
Speaker 49: subtext. Oh,
of
Speaker 173: course. For
any
Speaker 49: politically charged joke at all at the Oscars, right? It's going to be Trump adjacent ultimately. And that's the ultimate
Speaker 56: culprit for this non...
Speaker 56: non-prosecution of pedophiles, which we're
Speaker 70: told is like the most damning indictment that any society can ever be charged with.
Speaker 86: So in addition to everything that happened this weekend with Tucker, once that came out,
And
Speaker 86: this is another thing I wanted to ask you about, Michael, like people will immediately come to conclusions before they even hear what the story is. Right. So, you know,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Candace Owens came out with a tweet like almost immediately after Tucker's thing that said, if they come for Tucker, we ride at dawn.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): really nothing else
Speaker 68: to say here we're not doing the Gulags 2.0 with these Bolshevik
Speaker 39: descendants and I guess Bolshevik descendants is the new
Speaker 15: Zionist or something like that it's the new I mean it's thinly veiled
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): code for Jews I guess I don't know it's very strange right
Speaker 39: but
We
Speaker 39: write it down and then there were all these pledges of solidarity. And look,
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): I'm I am I've always been supportive of journalists who are the subject of unwarranted, you know, attention from the intelligence community,
Speaker 39: including Tucker when that happened. And, you know, if if that turns out to be the case here, absolutely, it's it's totally
Speaker 68: inappropriate. I don't think it's unbelievable, but I.
Speaker 68: Nobody knows what the alleged
Speaker 174: charges all the people have is this relatively slimmed down version of an account from Tucker. We
Speaker 175: write it to dawn like what
is this
Speaker 175: like Mad Max or something and right.
Speaker 152: Yeah, exactly. And this is and so these like crew of podcasters are going to get
Speaker 56: on there like.
Speaker 56: nitro charged uh humvee or something and ride off into this like dystopian hellscape to go what extricate tucker from the cia dungeon that's being guarded by some israeli demonoids or whatever
Speaker 39: right right yeah exactly exactly and then um and
so um
okay
Speaker 39: here's the problem
Speaker 86: with that like the the thing that really drove people crazy about the quote-unquote mainstream media in 2016 was the presumption that uh there was like a secret deal behind the scenes
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): that everybody was going to gang up on trump and there was like solidarity about this is that again this is what that moral clarity journalism thing was um
and
But
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): now podcasters
Speaker 174: are doing it. Now they're all banding together.
Speaker 86: And if you step off the reservation, then they're doing the same
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): disciplinary stuff that happened to people who are in the regular media. And I say
Speaker 68: that as somebody who was squeezed out of the regular media.
And
Speaker 68: now this is happening in independent media. So
Speaker 39: let's look at SOT4. This is Megan. So Megan Kelly. And she's talking about what happened to
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Tucker. And everybody's got to be on the team now. So let's hear
Speaker 176: what she has to say.
This is
Speaker 177: stunning and deeply wrong. And I believe Tucker.
Some don't. I
Speaker 178 (lower-pitched voice): do. I
do.
I believe
Speaker 178 (lower-pitched voice): him completely because he wouldn't have zero interest in running out, making himself the center of any story, which he doesn't like to do ever, even when he often is. And knowing him, I detected real concern in his voice there because he's worried about what's happening to our government. Like, why are we behaving like this? Why would we be going after private citizens, a journalist in Tucker's case, for investigating the war?
I mean,
Speaker 178 (lower-pitched voice): if Tucker, he says he spoke with sources in Iran prior to the conflict getting launched, that's something you would do if you had sources in Iran, you want to find out what was happening on the ground there. In order
Speaker 88: to violate the Foreign Agent Registration Act, you have to be acting on behalf of a foreign principle. You have to have you have to actually
Speaker 179: be like doing their bidding in an actual relationship.
I mean,
Speaker 33: look, if it does turn out that Tucker's account
Speaker 46: of this is 100% accurate, which is possible. I'm not saying it's probable at this point, but it is possible. If
that comes to
Speaker 46: pass, then, yeah, I would join
Speaker 19: the brigades of people denouncing it as well. Yeah, absolutely. The
Speaker 180: problem is that they do it in the first 10 seconds, and we don't even know what it is yet.
Speaker 181: We don't have any yet. There's no...
Speaker 181: adequate grounds to be making these kinds of like definitive
Speaker 123: statements yet and as we mentioned earlier there are some grounds to be a little bit dubious as to whether we're being told has been relayed accurately or accurately enough that
Speaker 111: we could just like go on the assumption that it must be
true
Speaker 124: yeah it could be it could be incorrect it could be slightly off you
Speaker 182: know you never know somebody told
Speaker 46: him something that maybe got spun a little
Speaker 46: bit and then something's lost in translation i mean there's a bunch of different explanations that range from like sinister
Speaker 10: and cynical to like good faith but accidental um who knows yeah i just think that you
Speaker 46: know her her but her preface there by saying tucker would have no reason to do this he would have no reason to make himself the center of attention really i mean yeah he kind of would
Speaker 79: because he
has this
Speaker 79: personal connection to donald trump right
Going
Speaker 10: back to the first term where he talked about how he would go and try to dissuade Trump from bombing Iran or whatever. And so it's this longstanding odyssey he's been on with Trump.
And it's
Speaker 123: perfectly explicable to me what he's doing, which is that he's trying to bolster this idea that
Speaker 49: the ultimate source of blame as he sees it for this blameworthy action that was taken, meaning the launching of the war with Iran, is ultimately...
is
Speaker 49: attributable to this interloper, nefarious interloper, meaning
Speaker 10: whoever is supporting the
interests of
Speaker 10: Israel against the pure hearted interests of the United States and has led Trump down this disastrous course. That's
the
Speaker 79: narrative that he's trying to propagate here.
So that's
And if
Speaker 123: he can, if he could give extra ammunition to that narrative by coming up with this exciting new subterfuge spy plot
Speaker 10: with the CIA and Israel. I mean,
look, I'm
Speaker 10: not saying that like he is consciously necessarily in his own mind motivated by a pure commercial incentive, but obviously
this is
Speaker 10: going to make a lot
Speaker 55: more people tune into the podcast. Right,
Speaker 183: right, right. And.
Speaker 183: Look, that's a whole
Speaker 65: other aspect of the whole mainstream press versus podcast thing. Just to answer, to
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): respond to at Whitney's Street House for a second. So Candace is stupid. Her listeners are stupid. Tucker and his listeners are stupid. Anyone who questions Israel's motives and behavior
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): is stupid. I'm getting tired of being called stupid. No, it's the other way
Speaker 113: around.
Yeah.
Speaker 113: If you have any reservations about any of this stuff,
Speaker 86: you know, you're you're called, you know, all kinds of crazy names and you're you're basically denounced as a as a traitor and unpatriotic. I mean, you know, we saw we saw the bizarre exchange
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): with Jimmy Dore.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): and Alex Jones, where, you know, Jimmy's saying, you know, Alex, people, they, you understand why they have, you know, you have a $1.5 billion debt, legal debt, and people naturally wonder whether, you know, you disagreeing with Candace has something to do with that. You
Speaker 174: know, that's where people are coming from now. Like, there's this whole thing where everybody's policing I don't know.
Speaker 174: what your proper approach should be to all these different issues. If I disagree with Candace Owens, first of all, it shouldn't be that big of a deal to you, right? Like to a normal person,
you know,
It
Speaker 174: shouldn't be a deal breaker with any individual. But now it's like this whole basically bouquet of interrelated theories that everybody's got to have or else
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): they're on the other side of something. And that's the part that's crazy, I think.
Speaker 123: Yeah, I'm certainly not saying and have never said that anybody who, quote, questions
Speaker 79: Israel's motives is stupid. Are you kidding me?
Speaker 79: I've I mean, I went to Israel shortly after October 7th and among other things, got my ass kicked by
Speaker 10: the stormtroopers who report to this Ben Gavir guy. So the actual messianic settler government minister who runs the internal security apparatus. I went to the West Bank. You know, I talked to lots of people with lots of different perspectives.
many
Speaker 10: of whom were very much critical of Israel. And 99% of what I've ever said in the public domain about Israel and U.S.
Speaker 79: foreign policy in relation to Israel has been critical, okay?
But that doesn't
Speaker 46: therefore mean I'm going to co-sign whatever nonsense blather that Candace Owens cooks up in her hallucinatory
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): mania where she's bringing in the Freemasons, she's bringing in some kind of pedophile,
Speaker 123: satanic, something or other,
Speaker 123: I mean, this is just garbage, and Tucker kind of absorbs
Speaker 46: a lot of it that's coming from the Candace-style direction. Maybe he's a little bit more intelligent and savvy and presentable than
Speaker 10: Candace, so he doesn't go quite as off the deep end as she is, but he's edging close to the deep end and is in
it already
Speaker 10: in certain respects. It's hard for anybody to really match Candace because she's just
like...
I don't
Speaker 10: even know how to characterize her at this point, but I resent that just because you associate now, and this is another one
of the
Speaker 10: huge, I think, corruptions of the current media
Speaker 46: ecosystem, just because you now associate any and all criticism with Israel, with your favorite handful of podcasters or pie column podcast creatures with outsized platforms.
And
Speaker 46: that's your own perceptual problem that hopefully I can help you sort of work through,
because there
Speaker 46: is a rational critique to be made of Israel, of U.S. foreign policy in relation to Israel, of Israel's role in the current conflict. I just object to this avalanche of sheer stupidity that people think they can just validate because they already have this preexisting disdain for Israel or suspicion of Israel. No, that's not a get out of jail free card to just spew whatever...
It
Speaker 46: is idiocy
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): you think that You're entitled to spew So and then with Tucker in particular it goes Hand in hand with him doing this whole Sort of obfuscation Charade where He's trying to deflect
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): agency or ascriptions of agency
Speaker 46: to donald trump the current commander-in-chief who is like unfettered control right now of the executive branch and is the commander-in-chief and is like talking about all the territories he wants to
Speaker 55: stomp through the world seizing like tucker can absolve him of any responsibility for anything because he just happens to love personally donald trump or just feels
so so personally
Speaker 55: fond of him and then just redirect everything
Speaker 46: onto israel and Not even a rational understanding of Israel, but this, again...
a
Speaker 79: histrionic cartoon of israel that just serves tucker's short-term political purposes and also probably commercial purposes so that's my response to
Speaker 70: whatever misguided person wrote that
Speaker 184: comment yep
Speaker 70: um okay
a couple
Speaker 86: other quick things any comment on the on
Speaker 185 (lower-pitched voice): the megan kelly mark levin micropenis
Speaker 185 (lower-pitched voice): uh incident no it's
Speaker 186: just another one of these proxy disputes you know megan went after me last last week first of
Speaker 10: all
first of all
Speaker 10: i don't need to hear megan talking about anybody's penis size much less mark levin's mark levin's okay i never
Speaker 79: wanted to even think about mark levin in relation to what size his penis may or may not be but like that's what that's what right wing in particular online media debate is now it's just this constant soap opera between this like handful of right way of
Speaker 79: media personalities
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): and like where's the meat or what where's the beef you know the wendy slogan that's an unfortunate uh maybe so where's the pizza
Speaker 120: where's the beef
Speaker 187: jerky that's right yeah where's
i
Speaker 180: mean because like it really i mean it just doesn't really have all that much substantive content to me other
than this
Speaker 79: non-stop non-stop spiraling soap opera thing that i guess is working out well for them in terms of generating an audience
But I
Speaker 79: can't understand how people actually are interested enough in to make this their like primary
Speaker 188: media diet.
Speaker 189: Yeah. So we got micropenis Mark here, thinks he has the monopoly on lewd. He tweets about me
Speaker 168 (lower-pitched voice): excessively in the crude as nasty as terms possible, literally more than some stalkers I had arrested. He doesn't because then Trump came
Speaker 190 (lower-pitched voice): out and did a truth social post where he basically sided with Mark Levin. Yeah. Can
we
Speaker 66: see that? That's that's also number 17. I think do we do we have that?
Speaker 66: And then
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): there was a, somehow Greenwald was commenting on the whole thing.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): But while they arranged that, just to get
to our
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): sort of last discussion in the night. Okay, here we go. By the way,
Speaker 190 (lower-pitched voice): Trump was
on a...
Speaker 190 (lower-pitched voice): even for him he was on a tirade he was on a tirade on on uh on truth social uh just block after
Speaker 191: block and block
after
Speaker 56: block of just texts right with interspersed with the all caps i mean he
doesn't
Speaker 192: even give it he doesn't even do paragraph indentation so people can read it a little easier so i'm not
Speaker 68: necessarily against that like obviously i'm a big fan of of that writer nicolai gogel who had
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): eight pages without paragraph breaks i'm not so sure it works as well with Trump
and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): um but his his true social game has
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): gotten really intense lately um he uh he seems to there seems to be a real thing
Speaker 68: with um uh arousal at military strike videos there's a lot of ed ads in there um i was a little surprised at that uh okay let's what is what is this
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): part that we're being asked to read uh mark mark levin was not looking to do television radio or anything else but he was drafted by very smart people
who understand
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): understood that there are few like him he is a true conservative and intellect far smarter than those who
Speaker 27: criticize him but above all he is a man of great wisdom and common sense but what's what's the thing about capitalizations with trump i don't
Speaker 193: know
i kind
Speaker 193: of like i kind of like the totally
Speaker 193: random capitalization i sort of mimic that myself occasionally yeah
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): when you hear others unfairly attack mark well remember that they are jealous and angry human beings who sway is much less than the public understands and well now that they know where i stand rapidly diminish um so
Speaker 46: this is just
The
Speaker 46: right-wing pundits who agree
Speaker 10: with me on the Iran war, they're true MAGA because I'm true MAGA. I determine what MAGA is. MAGA does not exist separately or independently of me, which is true enough in practical terms. And
because
Speaker 56: Mark Levin is a huge advocate of the Iran war and had been encouraging Trump to do it. Now, Mark Levin is true MAGA and anybody else in the right-wing media ecosystem who might be...
Speaker 56: registering some skeptical notes about it they are not true market so that's what that's the basically the fundamental reason why trump is saying what he's saying here
yeah
Speaker 196: uh matt this does seem
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): to be unfair to megan who has been repeatedly attacked by mark l i don't like how when uh when went after him but he has been a real dickhead
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): to her
Speaker 39: for quite a while. Okay, whatever. That's
kind of
Speaker 39: not the point. We're not taking sides in the argument. One thing I've never
Speaker 108: understood about Mark Levin is he's a radio host guy, right? So when I would be
Speaker 100: driving in my car, I would just listen to right-wing radio because that's all that was available if you want to listen to some kind of political talk radio.
And I
Speaker 100: could totally understand why people listen to a guy like Michael Savage, definitely a talented broadcaster,
Speaker 79: had sort of like
a...
Speaker 79: soothing or comforting voice in a way and maybe even Bill O'Reilly to
some extent but I
Speaker 79: never understood how people could sit there and listen to Mark Levin he's got the most obnoxious nasally almost like off-putting voice where he's just in a constant shrill sort of frenzy
and
Speaker 79: it's just horrible to listen to almost like acoustically so that's one thing i never got about him
Speaker 86: well i'm gonna back off from that one because i'm i i was born without the the broadcaster voice i know it because i grew up in a in a
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): household full of broadcasters and i i stood out um but okay the uh are
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): to dismount
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): So first of all, this is essentially going to be a preview of a thing we are going to do, which I'm going to just give a little hint about now. We're going to have a March
Speaker 39: Madness tournament to crown the worst podcaster in the country.
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): the
Speaker 197: details will be released. Are we still doing that? I wasn't even sure. We are still doing
Speaker 68: that. So we'll release the brackets later
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): this week. There's going to be a write-up of some of the early action. The regionals have already been concluded. You guys didn't hear about it. But...
Part
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): of what we're going to get into in
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): some of that sports coverage is this larger question, because you tweeted something, I guess it was last Friday, actually, but can we see Michael's tweet on the subject, or not the Brendan Carr thing, the...
i think
Speaker 198: it's number one this tweet i
Speaker 56: actually think was from a while ago it's like from mark from may of 2025 maybe but i just remembered it because we did we were discussing
Speaker 199: this topic yeah
Speaker 189: okay so if you had to choose one media diet and the choice was between
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): one legacy media with basic standards of journalistic verification however flawed or two just on critically imbibing the latest serving of the slop
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): fest podcast x algorithm
you
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): you'd have to choose one hands down. So, you know, like any... Do you disagree?
Speaker 68: Well, I would say that there's an argument for the other side. So allow me to retort. Okay. Media
is
Speaker 39: dangerous in... Basically
in
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): relation to how...
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): much impact it has and how believed it is, right? So the mainstream
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): press has the capacity to impact people on a much deeper level because people believe,
you know,
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): that there are standards there, right? So that when they fuck
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): something up, it tends to have a deeper and more longer, like a longer lasting
Speaker 200 (lower-pitched voice): impact. Now we're in
an,
Speaker 200 (lower-pitched voice): this place we're in right now where
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): the podcast world is by far driving uh the news cycle like the
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): audiences don't uh you know don't even compare uh in the old mainstream press
Speaker 136 (lower-pitched voice): they're minuscule in comparison but really
i mean
Speaker 201: do we know like do we know so if we tally up the
Speaker 49: subscribers or daily viewers of like the new york
times
wall
Speaker 49: street journal washington post cnn nbc abc etc
Speaker 10: that that it would be dwarfed obviously by the like this podcaster
set i
Speaker 10: think well
cable
Speaker 202: definitely would be
Speaker 33: cable news sure
yeah
Speaker 202: but the new york times is
Speaker 55: always doing fantastically well somehow meaning it's getting even bigger and i mean it has seven million
Speaker 36: like seven eight million subscribers i don't know It's something
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): like that.
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): You know, the numbers for a Rogan or a Tucker are just way beyond the
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): capacity of anything but broadcast television. And a lot of what broadcast, the numbers for broadcast are a
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): little bit skewed because
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): in many parts of the country, that's the only thing that people can access. Certainly online,
One
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): could
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): argue that the BBC and the New York Times
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): drives the news cycle as much as any podcasters do. But I think now, right now, just audience-wise, the biggest
Speaker 136 (lower-pitched voice): cable shows just don't have the same... Sure, sure. Whatever
Speaker 49: the exact proportionality of it is, it's clear, obviously, that...
this
Speaker 49: podcast media milieu it
has
Speaker 46: to
Speaker 10: be has to be seen as pretty if not you know pretty much on
the same
Speaker 10: level as the mainstream media if not having
Speaker 56: supplanted it just in terms of sheer influence and like what drives the news etc so like you can't just if you're doing a media critique nowadays right
Speaker 10: and all you did was focus on complaining about the new york times complaining about
cnn you'd
Speaker 10: almost be in this like
Speaker 10: delusional time warp or something
Speaker 56: right because you would have failed to update your priors for what is actually driving people's belief formation process about the world
Speaker 204: like based on what media they
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): consume yeah so uh there was a reason in 2024 that you know dana white thanked
Speaker 153: theo von
and
You know, Joe
Speaker 153: Rogan was the most coveted political endorsement in the country, essentially. Right.
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): Right. Exactly. Busting with the boys. Right. Like they all
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): got nods. And it's because their audiences, you know, are.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): just we're just much bigger right like kamala harris not doing uh the rogan show was was probably a catastrophic decision on her her part although doing it might have been a catastrophic decision on her part too so but either way podcasts are now in a place that they've never been which is leading the news as opposed to reacting to it and all i would say is the that the the notion that that the mainstream press, first of all,
that it has
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): uh minimal standards
Speaker 77 (lower-pitched voice): there's a that's a little bit illusory because that's not always true like having worked in the mainstream
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): press i've been in both situations where there's zero fact checking and where there is intense fact checking and like the the big story
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): that should have come out of episodes like stephen glass and jason blair is that that can happen because nobody's looking right
Speaker 68: um you can you can
you can
Speaker 68: Write total bullshit in
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): a mainstream publication and get away with it for a fairly long time, especially now.
But
Speaker 181: Stephen Glass and Jason
Speaker 10: Blair, those are sort of exceptions to the rule. I mean, those are cases of outright concerted long-term fraud, which is different than just
Speaker 129: flawed standards for determining whether something is true enough to publish or whether
the...
The
Speaker 10: narrative that it's propounding is something that is credible, right? So like the Russiagate stories in the first Trump administration, you'd be hard-pressed to find like a fact claim that was strictly wrong in those articles. The problem was that they
Speaker 49: added up to a narrative or they kind of created this collage of a of a
Speaker 10: theory almost.
That
Speaker 10: advanced people toward thinking that something was true that was fundamentally false, right? So that can happen in the mainstream media. I'm just saying that, you know, for example, I did a column in the Wall Street Journal, you know, a week
Speaker 56: and a half ago. I had to go through a pretty laborious editing process to confirm that everything that I wrote
in there was good to
Speaker 79: go, you know. And so I'm not saying that there aren't problems with the ordinary fact-checking process someplace, right?
Speaker 110: Um, but they, I'm just saying there are layer, there are, there are, there are, it is at least
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): like an aspiration towards some degree
Speaker 46: of editorial oversight or checking or lay. I mean,
it's just
Speaker 46: not like a no man's land or a free for all, which is what the online independent media is where like, there's not even an expectation that
Speaker 79: anything will ever be checked. Well,
Speaker 205: that's true. Okay. So,
Speaker 101: but, but
here's how
Speaker 101: lying works in the main, just say anything.
Speaker 101: you yeah with podcasts you can
Speaker 86: just say anything in in in the mainstream
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): press here's how you lie you you you call up an anonymous source who lies right uh you
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): print that uh you wink and nudge at the audience and pretend that
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): you um that
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): you honestly believe uh their version of events right so somebody calls up and says
um
You
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): know, all the spies in Russia went dark this weekend, right? That was a big headline story in the New York Times. There's no way to confirm that, right?
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): It's just something that somebody in one of the agencies told you, or Bounty Gate. Remember that,
Speaker 113: right? Yeah, Afghanistan. Yeah, so that was a thing. But they do also completely lie.
Speaker 113: not infrequently so let me i mean i should
Speaker 111: i should make clear that none of my critiques here of the alternative media or the online media or the
Speaker 10: podcast creatures should be under should be read as meaning that i'm exonerating the mainstream media or traditional media right or um i'm just saying that like if i had to choose like if you had to put a gun to my head and i had to
say
Speaker 10: one way or another what i want to get
if i
Speaker 10: want to when i want to get my information solely from the traditional media or solely from the online independent media i would have to go with the traditional media just because because at least
there's some
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): nominal aspiration toward fact-checking things like what yeah i mean i read the bounty gate stuff and because i used some discernment i could discern that this was phony
right but i
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): don't know
that i'm
And that kind
Speaker 56: of discernment would get me anywhere if I was trying to figure out what was true or what was false, listening to a Joe Rogan thing on the Epstein files, right? I mean, let
me just
Speaker 56: give you one quick example.
Speaker 79: This is, I just happened to come across this today for whatever reason. This
is Joe
Speaker 79: Rogan's podcast in January of 2024, okay? This is his UFC buddy or whatever, Eddie Bravo is on with him. And here's what Eddie Bravo says.
and
Speaker 79: again this was you know over two years ago quote i think everything that's going on in the world right now is linked to jeffrey epstein that's what
Speaker 10: i think the people that are on the list so he's somehow asserting that he knows that there's an epstein list or a client list and that would become to come to be widely believed because like stuff percolates outward from the joe rogan show and people
just assume it to be
Speaker 49: true because then other people repeat it or whatever he says the people
Speaker 46: that are on the list would rather if they had a choice
- Yeah.
You
Speaker 46: want to go to jail for this shit as a pedophile, or would you rather have World War Three? World War Three would save them. So this is him setting up this framework for
Speaker 10: understanding events in the world as fundamentally about the people on the Epstein list colluding together to ensure that they're not exposed for their pedophilic sex trafficking crimes, and they're willing to go so far as to instigate World
Speaker 79: War Three
to keep
Speaker 79: themselves out of jail.
And
Speaker 79: so like, that's kind of relevant now because that's essentially what people think is going on with the
Speaker 208: Middle East war.
And I just
Speaker 208: think that, you know, that could be rationalized.
As can a million other
Speaker 157: things that have been on the Joe Rogan show recently in the minute,
this is
Speaker 157: the biggest audience on the internet. So it's not just mean cherry
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): picking or arbitrarily focusing on somebody. Oh, of course. Yeah. Biggest audience on the internet. And that could be
rationalized as
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): well, Joe Rogan, he's just a comedian, man.
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): He's just this dopey, fun-loving guy who's,
Speaker 46: like, curious about the world and he'll talk to anybody. He's
not a
Speaker 46: journalist, right? So Joe Rogan is immediately
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): exempted from having to do any fact-checking of anything ever. And he could just, you know, transmit out the most insane
Speaker 79: crap constantly no matter how unbelievably wrong it is just on a pure, factual level. And then...
no
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): problem, because he's not a journalist, right? At least if you say that you're a journalist on some level, then
that comes
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): with an assumption that like you're at least required kind of to make sure that you check out what you're saying is factual before you just blur it out, but not with him and not with all his ancillary
Speaker 110: podcast colleagues who form this whole ecosystem. So that's like part of the
crux of my
Speaker 110: critique here, I guess I would
say.
I
Speaker 86: absolutely agree with you. And for those, again, just to reiterate why
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): it is that we're doing this show. Michael
and I
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): both, I think, come together.
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): We're living sort of
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): historical specimens left over from a time when people in the media were trained not to say anything on television that could get them sued or in trouble. Right. So you
Speaker 121: would never go on the air directly.
Speaker 121: like did you ever have media training Michael did you ever do that
Speaker 210: media training
Speaker 129: no no he
Speaker 211: never did that whole thing
Speaker 212: where they say okay
Speaker 129: I skipped whatever brainwash meeting you're talking about where did you get media training at Rolling Stone no no no it's a
Speaker 212: thing where they where they bring in some person was yawn runners
Speaker 129: like okay Matt so uh here's our bottom line and we got to make sure that uh
Speaker 213: the lawyers
Speaker 129: are
Speaker 129: The
Speaker 213: lawyers charge a lot per hour, so don't get us into a situation
Speaker 79: where X, Y, Z, something like that.
Speaker 214: No, no, no.
Media
Speaker 79: training. I would love, is that on video
Speaker 42: by any chance? Can I watch you being media trained? No,
Speaker 215: I hope not. No,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): media training is actually not about the legal aspect. It's almost entirely about getting people who are uncomfortable on television to look better on television. So they give you all these tricks.
um
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): to get you through segments so so they'll tell you okay pick three things that you're going to say no matter what uh and just deliver those when the
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): questions are asked um so that you don't focus too much on uh you know on some sandbagging question or something like
that but
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): um as part of media training they they do kind of tell you to stay behind the line in terms of things that you're not sure about.
If
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): you venture into an area
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): where factually you can't remember or you don't know whether somebody was
Speaker 45: charged or not in a case or whatever it is, just don't go there at all. Maybe
Speaker 213: hedge or qualify or just don't say something authoritatively that you can't be sure is true.
Speaker 36: Exactly. So we're not going to do that in this space anymore.
Speaker 36: And
Speaker 113: my guess is that there aren't going to be many places like that left very soon.
Speaker 99: The online media world right now lives and breathes on excitable
Speaker 79: conjecture, basically, as what they're putting out there day after day.
And look,
Speaker 79: I know it's fun to speculate about
Speaker 10: stuff and theorize, and I'm not above
it.
Speaker 10: theorizing about things, if I can have like an ample factual basis for inferring something potentially. Right. So I'm not just like this. I'm not just kind of like paralyzed into only doing just the facts, ma'am. And
Speaker 49: I can never say anything beyond that. But the over-reliance on this wild conjecture, I think,
is a big
Speaker 49: problem because
it has
Speaker 49: loosened the standards for what people perceive to be
Speaker 46: sufficient evidentiary
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): basis to go out in public and just say stuff because now you can just say anything it doesn't matter oh i know
Speaker 86: you just you pull it out of you know
you just
Speaker 86: pull it out of your ass and and the thing is now you pull it out of
Speaker 111: your ass and then people then lo and behold people end up believing that
there's a
Speaker 10: mass scale child rape atrocity
And
Speaker 10: pedophilic sex trafficking network that is like the organized that like dictates how the entire world is governed, essentially, and also explains why, you know, Trump bombed Iran
and X,
Speaker 10: Y and Z.
So like
Speaker 10: it has consequences not to be a downer, but like this radical loosening in any and all standards is not just
like...
you
Speaker 10: know a thought exercise for us to think about like what might be better i'm you know my my assertion is anyway that it's actually having a now observable serious repercussions
Speaker 217: yeah among
Speaker 10: other things are like distorting
Speaker 204: people's ability to perceive like what the united states military is doing
at the
Speaker 218: moment absolutely
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): yeah and
and
You
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): mentioned Rogan, right? Like biggest audience in the universe. I know you're not a big fan of Michael Schellenberger, but I just never
Speaker 219: I just never I could
Speaker 79: never quite put my finger on what I found just a little off about him. I don't want to go any further than that. Like there's some stuff that I've seen subsequently, but I don't know. It's just I can't quite articulate what my
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): reservations have been about him over the
years.
I like
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): Michael I've worked I've worked with him
Speaker 121: before obviously we worked in the Twitter files before but he went on Joe's show and when he expressed a few reservations about
Speaker 200 (lower-pitched voice): some aspect of the Epstein thing I forget what part it was
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): but he wrote an article saying we had assumed like he's speaking in the royal we I don't even know who he's referring
Speaker 10: to exactly but like we our team here at wherever they are.
Speaker 10: assume that epstein was an intel asset running a
Speaker 181: honeypot thing and now we're not so sure so wait a second why had you assumed that initially so again like there's something there's something even weird epistemically going on with
him
Speaker 220: too yeah so whatever uh but yeah rogan says what
Why
Speaker 220: are you resisting this? I don't
Speaker 47: understand why you're resisting this. So it's this disciplinary thing
Speaker 221: where it's...
Speaker 47: Do not stop resisting.
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Yeah, exactly. Which is the thing that we used to get on the case about, you know, mainstream press about, which is that you either said the things or you didn't get the green room
Speaker 41 (lower-pitched voice): invites again. Like, you know, Glenn Greenwald, Aaron Mate, I'm assuming you had this experience as well. We were all sort
Speaker 222: of...
Speaker 222: universally not invited back on television as of the beginning of Russiagate, right? Except the
Speaker 223: Fox, except the Tucker Show.
Speaker 222: Yeah, except the Tucker Show. I guess
Speaker 223: we've come full circle now or something. I don't know. So,
Speaker 39: but now the podcast is doing that, but they're doing it with wackier shit. So,
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): by the way, I just want to give kudos to at Bart 93 49 for the Kenneth, what is the frequency reference?
Speaker 224: Michael, do you know that story?
Yeah.
I
Speaker 224: know the R.E.M. song. What's the frequency Kenneth? Okay
Speaker 225: that comes from this thing where I know it comes from something but I can't tell you exactly what it comes from. Dan Rather got I believe
Speaker 226: he got the blog. Oh yeah it comes from Dan Rather yeah yeah yeah okay I did remember that.
And
Speaker 39: the people as they were working him over the only thing they said was Kenneth what is the frequency and nobody to
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): this day knows what that means which I think is one of the funnier stories that has ever happened
in
Speaker 113: media anyway yeah
Speaker 113: So, yeah, so this podcast
Speaker 51: thing is, you know, it's happening at a moment when extraordinary
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): complicated events are happening every five minutes with new developments that are, you know,
that...
even
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): in the best of times when the networks had bureaus in every major city in the world would be difficult to cover. And now we have absolutely
Speaker 227: no, no idea what the hell is going on.
Speaker 46: And let me give you, and now that these, the podcast creatures have grown
so
Speaker 10: outsized in their influence and are like sucking
up,
media
Speaker 10: resources that might otherwise theoretically be more evenly distributed so we can have maybe some foreign bureaus or something where they could go to the street of Hormuz and let us know what's going on with certain things right about now. Let
me give
Speaker 10: you another argument for why it's
to
Speaker 56: rely solely on the podcasters than the more traditional media. And again, this is not me absolving the traditional media for all its historic wrongdoing,
but
Speaker 100: audience capture or audience susceptibility, right? Or susceptibility to audience-driven incentives. So just here's one example from relatively recent past. Remember when, but right before
Speaker 10: the 2024 election, the Washington Post editorial board was going to put out its obvious endorsement of Kamala Harris. And then Jeff
Speaker 56: Bezos
and
Speaker 56: then just nixed the whole editorial. And then hundreds of thousands of Washington Post subscribers fled
Speaker 79: en masse. So that's a lot of subscribers and a lot of money potentially fleeing. And that's just not something... So, I mean, I could never...
Speaker 79: necessarily
Speaker 10: glean anything that was done differently after that in terms of the Washington Post editorial philosophy that would suggest that they were trying to compensate for the thousands of hundreds of thousands of subscribers they lost or whatever. They just kind of plugged along, right? And yeah, it was a Jeff
Speaker 79: Bezos intervention from the top, but it's just not something I could ever see happening at a independent media outfit where it's like probably centered it on one person.
Speaker 79: And their personality
where
Speaker 10: they're much more acutely cognizant of and reactive to audience incentives, meaning the daily
Speaker 49: fluctuations in subscriber counts, in views, in downloads, whatever.
Speaker 228: And there's not
Speaker 46: even a pretense that there's any kind of firewall whatsoever between the business side and the editorial side, right? At least
Speaker 79: there's a pretense of that within these more mainstream or traditional media entities.
Yeah, and
Speaker 65: look, this was something that sub-stackers
Speaker 7: were aware of immediately when a lot of people who came over from the media were like,
Speaker 7: there's this thing where you can look at the graph
Speaker 52 (lower-pitched voice): and see how much money you're making um and it's you know for for some people they come over here and um
let's
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): just say a very well-known journalist uh his line to me when upon moving to substack originally was this is the best thing since penicillin um
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): you can see you know the the
And
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): it's incredible. Conversely, when it starts going the other way.
Speaker 113: Now, what do I do now? What do I do now? The only thing the only way to honestly deal with that moment is to just embrace the fact that you're
Speaker 86: going to lose money
and.
Speaker 86: And potentially friends and people who might retweet you and all these other things because when you start saying
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): – when you don't go along with the current thing, the punishments have escalated now. I probably
Speaker 77 (lower-pitched voice): to my
Speaker 201: own detriment always at least tried not to even look too closely at the Substack metrics.
Speaker 230: No, I try. I
Speaker 10: don't even want to know. I definitely don't want to know who's subscribing, meaning who's a paid subscriber, because I don't even
Speaker 55: want to subconsciously
have the potential of
Speaker 55: like placating anybody. I know, but at the same
Speaker 10: time, though, you can't entirely avoid it, unfortunately. So like I get
Speaker 79: glimpses of it here and there. And like, I just know, like when I first started getting really immersed in the Epstein stuff, you know, last July, August, I got hammered by on every metric, on every platform.
Speaker 231: Um,
Speaker 79: but you
Speaker 49: know, I don't really care. Maybe
I'm in a
Speaker 49: position where I'm able to not care
so much. Cause I
Speaker 79: don't have like, for example, like four dependents. So it was like college tuitions I have to pay at the moment. Right. You know, so I have like my, my overhead is kind of low, but, um, so I can't necessarily begrudge others who might feel
like they're
Speaker 56: obliged to pay a little bit closer attention to it, but at least
I know
Speaker 56: for my own individual purposes,
um,
I've
Speaker 56: just always like tried to create a mental firewall,
which takes some
Speaker 233: deliberate effort. Like it's not just something that you just naturally happen in a half. You have to
Speaker 86: work through that actually you got. And so I'm willing to take the pledge right now that if anybody catches
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): me giving a fuck about audience from this point forward, you know,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): I unsubscribe immediately because, honestly, I've come to the realization and it was not easy. It's been like a years long process trying to work through how all this works. There is no
way to
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): do this if you're looking at the numbers and you're paying
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): attention to
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): what the algorithm is doing because the algorithm by the way is
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): fickle and you know there are it changes pretty regularly depending I remember something while
Speaker 234: do you do you have to like when when the Twitter files first happened so that was
Speaker 46: like December of 2022
is that
Speaker 46: right
Speaker 235: yeah yeah
I
Speaker 46: remember just because I was like tweeting some stuff that was supportive of
Speaker 46: the Twitter files. And I was like perceived maybe to be like in your network to some
Speaker 79: extent. I don't even know how you define that. I remember getting like the biggest algorithmic boost I've ever gotten. And I wasn't even like directly involved in the Twitter files. So that didn't last forever.
Speaker 46: But like, yeah, it is incredibly fickle. And you can't tailor yourself to trying to anticipate what the latest sort of fluctuation in the algorithmic
Speaker 236: sort of
i don't
Speaker 236: know uh magic potion is going to
be well
Speaker 237: as you say there there are
Speaker 196: like nine elements right
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): now that that the algorithm likes if if you have any kind of news sense you can tell exactly what
Speaker 189: they are as you you mentioned one of them which is this demons ufos epstein israel israel
Speaker 164: right
Speaker 240: like mysticism uh you know apocalyptic uh predictions prophecies
Speaker 241: like future
Speaker 242: Like crystal ball, future prophecies. Secret societies, sort of
Speaker 243: like LaRouchean sort of
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): like basically
Speaker 68: back from the 70s and 80s type of theories. Those are all back. Like we're starting to see every
Speaker 86: now and then you'll see a new conspiracy theory or a new thing that becomes hot. Can we see the, and this can be our last thing that we react to
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): tonight.
Speaker 67 (lower-pitched voice): Can we see the Trump assassination conspiracy post? This had 15 million views. I think it's number 21. And it's from an account based somewhere
Speaker 168 (lower-pitched voice): in Europe. But I don't
know.
Speaker 168 (lower-pitched voice): essentially the the new idea is that the the
Speaker 227: donald trump uh attempted assassination was not real it was staged right people were saying
Speaker 244: that you know i mean there were some people there were there was some no but it's back we're saying that
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): yeah in a big way yeah
Speaker 168 (lower-pitched voice): yeah it came back and so look you know look at the number of views there right um that's a big number and
Speaker 85: uh
Speaker 85: And people pay attention to this stuff
Speaker 46: and... Well, you know what some of this is? This is like...
So I
Speaker 46: would say that in terms of the handful of things that are being algorithmically
Speaker 129: prioritized or amplified, in 2024, it was pro-Trump. I mean, it was this
Speaker 56: like Elon Musk-driven, Joe Rogan-driven, Theo Vaughn, conspiracism-adjacent...
Speaker 10: online quote-unquote anti-establishment RFK Tulsi Gabbard crowd of that whole tendency was hugely algorithmically incentivized in 2024 and the Republicans
Speaker 56: brilliantly operationalized that as part of their campaign strategy in 2024 so um but now what you see and I think there still hasn't been really a reckoning with that and a lot of people
who did not
Speaker 56: come away looking particularly good having bought into that but now what you see
Speaker 56: what's that
Speaker 225: including me i mean i felt i i fell for certain things okay
Speaker 247: okay yeah maybe we'll get into it at some point in more depth if you can you know i mean i
Speaker 76: didn't misreport anything but no no i got you yeah there were definitely things that i that i uh i just know
i
Speaker 46: just i just know i got on on in on the in the 2016 election right when trump won not that i was happy
So
Speaker 46: per se, but I felt almost like a kind of jubilation just in that a lot of the stuff that I had been
told I
Speaker 46: was
Speaker 10: crazy for diagnosing about the electorate or like projecting outward in terms of like a likely outcome had been proven right on some level.
And I
Speaker 10: know a lot of people in hindsight try to claim it. They're always right about the 2016 election. It's mostly BS. But me, I mean, I'll show
you like
Speaker 56: the stuff that I was saying, like,
Speaker 56: pretty very early on i think you and i had talked about this where you had written off trump in 2016 and
Speaker 248: well my arc was
Speaker 121: worse i i was dead right about him first then then i renounced myself in the middle of the race what after the access
Speaker 249: hollywood tape or something or
Speaker 250: no no no i i got talked out of it by a pollster at the at the convention uh
but
Speaker 251: my my first article was was about how America made Trump unstoppable. And that was
Speaker 42: like- - But in 2024, right?
Speaker 42: before much different I felt just a palpable sense of dread I felt like
Speaker 10: there was something really bad going on here that for some reason people in the media who otherwise I had been had this kinship with had systematically chosen to ignore or even to to validate
the
And some of
Speaker 10: these misconceptions around Trump that are, that were catering to that algorithmically incentivized demographic at the time. And I just had like a
pit in my
Speaker 10: stomach pretty much about it. Um, I'll, you know, a lot of it was an omen. A lot of it was stuff that I could sort of detect
from the
Speaker 10: campaign. And, you know, again, I don't like to go around
Speaker 10: bragging as having been shown right about anything that's so because it always comes across as pompous but like a lot of what i did foresee has now come to pass and it's even more extreme probably than i would have anticipated i mean he's just talking today is he's gonna say yeah it's my great honor to take over cuba next as though
Speaker 10: He's just like crusading around the world, just like picking and choosing what territories. I don't
Speaker 51: think that shit plays as well now that he's actually.
Speaker 46: No, I'm saying, but so then you have this stuff, right? Exactly. So you have this stuff where people are now latching. They're now reviving this
Speaker 10: theory that maybe the assassination attempt was staged.
Speaker 252: Right. And
Speaker 10: so I think that's partially a function of that algorithmic consensus that congealed around him in 2024, fracturing,
Speaker 56: especially in,
in
Speaker 56: light of the iran war but it had there been sort of precursors to that even before february 28th but definitely after the iran war now you see all people who have been constituent parts of that consensus now like not knowing what to do or where to go so you have you know tucker's move is to say oh it's all israel or you have some more of the conspiracy sort of minded people saying oh maybe this
was all part of a
Speaker 56: long-standing plot that we missed and they staged the assassination It's a combination
attempt.
and I'm
Speaker 100: sure there's going to be a million other sort of layers to those kinds of theories that are going to emerge as people try to like reorient themselves into
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): something because right now they're sort of just floating out at sea and don't even like, no, they're just like swimming for lifeboats.
Speaker 254: Yeah, no, absolutely. Uh,
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): and you know, maybe what we could do on this show is we could have like a, like a sort of leaderboard or, uh, uh,
a
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): little display of what we think the algorithm likes to speak, right? You know, sort of like an ESPN style display
Speaker 200 (lower-pitched voice): at the bottom of the screen or something like that. Can
Speaker 255: we get the dun, dun, dun, dun, dun?
Speaker 256: Yeah, yeah, yeah,
Speaker 257: exactly. Matt thinks I'm
Speaker 256: like a guy who just doesn't like sports, so I won't get any sports references. No, that's not true. Just for
Speaker 10: everybody's information.
Speaker 10: I know I'm conversant enough about sports to be able to make
Speaker 79: small talk with like a guy at a gas station or something. Yeah. Or the bar or wherever.
Speaker 56: No, I'm not going to, I'm not the, I'm not a fancy football lunatic where like all my energy day in and day out is poured into
like
Speaker 80 (lower-pitched voice): finally fine tuning, which wide receiver is going to get the most points or something. I mean, I think that stuff is great.
Speaker 36: I was going to say like, I look, I'm already into who the sixth round receivers are. No. So
Speaker 258: you're out of your mind.
Speaker 39: Yeah, exactly.
Speaker 39: But otherwise, we're more or less on the same page. So, yeah, well,
maybe we
Speaker 39: could do something like that. Anyway, this is all a way of sort of introducing
Speaker 5: the fact that the next time you see us, it'll be likely a tape
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): segment, and it will be the first round of the March Madness tournament. and there'll be some texts that accompany
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): this um and um i don't know
Speaker 85: anything else michael anything else we need to get to uh what else do we need i don't know there's always something to get to uh oh we do have to mention uh the brendan carr
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): re-injected himself into the news uh
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): the FCC thing. And
Speaker 39: look, at this point, and this is one of the things I was wrong about, I thought my impression of
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): Trump on speech was not that he was a civil libertarian or that he grew up worshipping the ACLU or anything
Speaker 39: like that, but that he just didn't give a shit about it as much. And this
Speaker 39: uh the last year has been kind of a you know it's it's been a little bit of a surprise to me how how how much they're doing uh they're following in the footsteps of the
shit
Speaker 260: that they criticized i
Speaker 261: don't know they open i mean i know rfk would have had you believe otherwise or would have dissembled would have
Speaker 49: dissembled yeah or tulsi without or
Speaker 262: would have uh
I'm not
Speaker 49: quite so
Speaker 11: sure about him in terms of what I'm about to say right now, which is that they would have
told you
Speaker 11: that by voting to restore Republican executive
Speaker 256: power, you were voting to restore free speech, which to me was always
a joke, in part
Speaker 79: because Trump and the Republicans
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): were openly campaigning on drastically stymieing speech when it came to speech critical of Israel. OK, so that's the canary in the coal mine.
Speaker 134: Did they
Speaker 263: say that? Yes,
Speaker 134: absolutely. I mean, I'll give you a million examples where they were calling. I mean, they they campaigned on. Oh,
Speaker 264: using state power. Yeah. The anti-Semitism. Yeah, anti-Semitism stuff. It campaigned
Speaker 46: specifically on using the power of the state to to limit and punish speech that they deemed.
Speaker 137: excessively critical of israel and or anti-semitic
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): right well they expanded that anti-semitism awareness act which we i did write critically about uh at the time um
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): i just i i never thought it was as comprehensive like the the shit that goes into something like the digital services act and
Speaker 6 (lower-pitched voice): You know, the Online Safety Act in the UK, the laws in New Zealand, Australia, there's
Speaker 250: an underlying idea about all speech that is...
Speaker 250: Different from I thought different from what
Speaker 222: the Republicans would be up to. Oh, but, you
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): know, one of the things that was
Speaker 42: algorithmically at that would
have been
Speaker 42: at the top of the ESPN leaderboard, it was RFK Jr. For
a long time. And
Speaker 265: RFK
Speaker 42: Jr. Was the one who confected this whole mythology
Speaker 49: around, first of all, what he represented them, what he was subsuming into the Trump operation once
Speaker 10: they merged.
Speaker 10: And so you had stuff like, yeah, Trump is the champion of free
Speaker 46: speech because I'm the champion of free speech and we're going to work together in this Avengers squad with Tulsi and Elon and Joe Rogan to restore free speech.
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): And it was just like a total canard. And like at some point, people go back and watch the speeches that RFK delivered on behalf of Trump. No, I know. I
Speaker 266: mean, I was I was there for some of them. I
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): mean, it's just it's it's it's I just don't understand. I feel like there ought to be. Look, I'm not trying to be vindictive.
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): I just feel like if you were part,
not
Speaker 79: you personally, but if one was part of creating the impression to a mass audience that what RFK was describing
in terms
Speaker 79: of the nature of whatever
Speaker 46: that new coalition was,
if you were giving
Speaker 46: people the impression that that was like at all tethered in reality, that there should be some kind of reckoning done. Just like after the 2016 election, I was trying to get, I launched what I called a pundit accountability project with
Speaker 10: all these crazed liberal pundits who like Jamel Bowie, who of course got promoted
Speaker 10: afterwards when he should have been demoted but he would say look like he wrote a column
Speaker 56: saying there's a better chance that an asteroid will strike earth than donald trump will win the election well
yeah
Speaker 267: um remember
Speaker 56: um
Speaker 185 (lower-pitched voice): uh 538.com saying that there's a better chance that trump will play in the nba than win the nomination
or
Speaker 46: you know ryan grimm famously said look we're not covering we're not even going to cover trump in the politics section of the huff post we're going to cover him in the entertainment section because this is all just like a reality
Speaker 46: TV show shtick. So, yeah, I was I went after people for that stuff in the like in the in the like autopsy phase of the 2016 election. But there's been no desire to do that for the 2024 election, which, if anything, might even be more consequential in terms of the depth and breadth of the media failure, at least as
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): I see it, because you had RFK Jr. Having, you know, all this alt media, you know, all these all media people wrapped around his finger.
And he
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): went to the Madison Square Garden rally like a week before the election. Remember this? And he literally said that, you know, vote Trump if you want to end the warfare state.
Because like, and
Speaker 268: that should have been derided as crazy
at the
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): time.
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): What, you think, what, was Trump pledging not to do record-busting military budgets anymore, just like he did in the first
Speaker 111: term? Like, when did, how did RFK Jr. get the idea that Trump was going to roll back the scale of the military-industrial complex or anything in
Speaker 46: that vein? It was just total myth that he drew on his overrated family legacy to imbue himself with and then imbue Trump with. And it was just a total,
just, it's
Speaker 46: just crazy. And
I
Speaker 269: think, you know, there's got to be some accounting for it on some level. Because, like, I mean...
Speaker 269: mean, Trump just launched a giant war in the Middle East, like out of he
Speaker 270: did. And look, I didn't I didn't see that
Speaker 5: coming. And I I thought, you know, I was mistaken about
Speaker 248: certain things like I didn't think my rationale, my rationale about
Trump.
In
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): 2024 was different from all those people who it was based on the idea that there was something that was absolutely going to happen in the other direction and so any
Speaker 40 (lower-pitched voice): variable was better than that, at least on the speech front
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): like there were there, there was nothing.
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): really worse that could happen
Speaker 69: than what was being planned right so um but and now we
Speaker 11: have brandon carr saying hey if you're too mean about donald trump and his amazing performance as commander-in-chief as we wreck the iranian state and try to do regime change you better watch
Speaker 10: out because the fcc is coming for you which like even when they did this to kimmy jimmy kimmel after the
I
Speaker 10: mean, what I immediately said was I really resent the Trump administration right now because I really despise Jimmy Kimmel and they're forcing me into a position where I have to, quote, defend Jimmy Kimmel, even though like the stuff that he was saying about Charlie Kirk was dumb and wasn't even funny. But like this idea that he's going to have
the have
Speaker 10: state power now coming into politics.
Speaker 123: punish him is just not something that's tolerable. Although, you know, it got
Speaker 79: kind of quickly reversed. And like, who cares about Jimmy Kimball? I get it. But like now this is like much more, much higher stakes, right? Sure. Yeah. But I would, what I would counter with is,
is that, you know,
The laws
Speaker 271: that they already have in, say, Europe and Germany are already
Speaker 30 (lower-pitched voice): as bad as they can be, right? Like you can be raided and detained and put in prison or put in jail for any number
Speaker 81: of speech offenses at this point. We are not yet at that point.
But at
Speaker 81: this point, I don't doubt that we're headed in that tradition. I was all
Speaker 79: for the critiques of the Democrats, whether Biden, Harris, whomever, and their speech infringing policies, which were maybe a
Speaker 10: little bit more systematized and a little bit more well, you know, better polished in terms of how they enacted them. And they had the they had obviously the sign off of these people.
think
Speaker 10: tanks and like satellite
Speaker 79: organizations that were subsidized or given a grant or something. That's how the Democrats tend to do things. Right. So I was all for a thoroughgoing critique of that. I just never understood why that had to go hand in hand with
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): a fictitious representation of Donald Trump. Like why? Like why couldn't, I mean, I like the idea. Why can't we go back to journalists being crotchety people?
You
Speaker 104 (higher-pitched voice): know, despisers of everybody. Yeah, we've
Speaker 174: already had this discussion. You're right. You're absolutely right. You know, in hindsight,
Speaker 5: I did have a more nuanced way of thinking about that whole thing. But the idea for
Speaker 272: me was
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): never that Donald Trump was going to be some kind of savior on the speech front. It was just that...
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): any eventuality like even two bad speech models were better than one right like one unified one
Speaker 200 (lower-pitched voice): which is where they were headed right the whole idea was to have a single common database of offenders all over the world and everything like that like that scared the shit out of me and what the
Speaker 250: idea that that might be added to ai and all that other stuff
Speaker 273: Anyway, that's a different discussion. That's a different discussion. We can have this argument another time. But as people
Speaker 68: see, Michael and I are not afraid to disagree about things. And
I
Speaker 270: don't publicly
Speaker 274: think any less of him for it. Privately, you may well. Which, you know,
Speaker 275: I think of less of myself
Speaker 85: privately as well. No, I'm kidding. Obviously, I'm kidding. Michael, this was fun. Like, you know, this was...
Speaker 169: people
Speaker 85: hate
Speaker 42: it you know i feel like there's probably you know since i was told by one of the producer people to have like the comments scrolling this whole time which is
Speaker 10: like a major distraction but i've done it so i've
scanned some
Speaker 10: of them here and there i think i'm not sure what the reaction is i know a lot of people it's gonna don't want to hear anything bad
Speaker 74: about trump still so i don't know
Speaker 48: how that's gonna be something that's sustainable um well
i don't
Speaker 48: know
Speaker 11: like What do you think? How do you think the audience is receiving this...
new
Speaker 277: iteration of whatever your podcast streaming uh venture is
Speaker 185 (lower-pitched voice): they're they're still in mourning about um about america
this
Speaker 86: week uh no longer being here which is not something i can really do anything about
Speaker 278: and um and i
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): don't know anything about i mean i'll be honest i never i never like i don't listen to watch to virtually any podcast i never even saw
it
Speaker 279: right so i i'll
Speaker 155 (higher-pitched voice): read your stuff when it comes out
Speaker 48: but i'm not sitting around vegetating in front of these podcasts constantly which i know is hypocritical for me to say given that this is technically a podcast in some form but like that's my attitude so i had nothing to do with anything that went on before so
but
Speaker 3: but what i what i would say to people in the audience who might be feeling a a certain kind of
way is
Speaker 3: that um
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): you know i i i think
uh
Part of
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): the motivation for doing a show like this, I'm making a bet on the idea that eventually people are going to be freaked out and wonder where they
Speaker 61 (lower-pitched voice): can go to not be lied to or be sold some crazy ass batshit algorithm chasing theory.
Speaker 39: We're not going to do that to you. That might not be a sexy thing at the moment, but eventually,
Speaker 39: it
Speaker 68: might be a little bit reassuring I resent
Speaker 56: that the internet unanimously agrees that I'm a sexy king as
Speaker 108: I'm reminded of constantly given all the compliments I receive about my appearance well all well
Speaker 174: deserved no I'm kidding no this is fun Michael
Speaker 5: and look I
Speaker 5: as miserable as the dissent
Speaker 280: of the media landscape is, it's also going to be extremely funny to comment
Speaker 281: on. There's always
Speaker 280: going to be
Speaker 282: some dark humor
Speaker 280: available for Axis.
The amount of
Speaker 7: gallows humor material is basically going to be bottomless.
Speaker 103: And for
Speaker 10: all my growing annoyance, to say the least, with the independent media or the alt
media,
I
Speaker 10: mean, it's still the case that
I probably
Speaker 10: would be out of a job without it. So, like, I'm not going to try to claim that I'm somehow totally free of any of this or, like, absolved from all responsibility for anything.
Speaker 11: Like, I don't know. I wouldn't have made it. Like, I tried for a while, and nobody would give me a job at one of the mainstream outlets. So, look, I'm
Speaker 10: saddled with it as well. So I'm trying... I have a personal stake in the...
Speaker 10: comically
Speaker 13 (lower-pitched voice): gargantuan flaws now that are being made more and more manifest so that's part of my motivation for bringing attention
to
Speaker 284: them all right well either way we're
Speaker 16 (lower-pitched voice): we're going to have some fun going through all the craziness uh in the coming weeks and um uh i i personally
Speaker 15: promise that it will be funny so uh michael this was fun
Speaker 15: thanks for hanging out and we will see you again soon we'll let you
Speaker 31 (lower-pitched voice): know what the schedule is um at minimum there will be a a tape show at the end of the week but
Speaker 87 (lower-pitched voice): we might do another one between you you and i should talk about that okay
Speaker 285: whatever you want my my your wish is my command
excellent
Speaker 15: thank you everybody uh and we will see you soon all right take care